Communication off-camera
离机通讯
This is going to be fun.
这会很有趣。
.
。
All right.
好的。
Okay.
Right, so good evening, class.
好的，晚上好，同学们。
Right.
正确的。
This is the first time I'm here in such a big LT
这是我第一次来到这么大的LT
and see many of our students here.
在这里看到我们的许多学生。
So it's really a very big LT.
所以这确实是一个非常大的 LT。
Right, okay.
对了，好吧。
So welcome to this course,
欢迎来到本课程，
E6427, Video Signal Processing.
E6427，视频信号处理。
Right.
正确的。
So I'm actually Prof Yab.
所以我实际上是Yab教授。
I'm going to be the instructor for this course.
我将担任这门课程的讲师。
Right, so given here is my contact information.
好的，这是我的联系信息。
So should you have any question,
那么如果您有任何疑问，
you're welcome to drop me an email
欢迎您给我发电子邮件
and then we can talk about that.
然后我们就可以讨论这个问题了。
Okay.
好的。
Can you all hear?
你们都听得见吗？
Oh, yeah, sorry.
哦，是的，抱歉。
Okay, right.
好吧，对。
Let's probably do it one more time.
也许我们再做一次吧。
So welcome to E6427, Video Signal Processing.
欢迎来到 E6427，视频信号处理。
Right, so I'm Prof Yab.
是的，我是 Yab 教授。
I'm going to be the instructor for this course.
我将担任这门课程的讲师。
So given here is my contact information.
这里给出的是我的联系信息。
So should there be any question
那么还有什么问题吗
that you would like to ask regarding this course,
您想询问有关本课程的问题，
you can drop me an email.
你可以给我发电子邮件。
For the past one week or so,
过去一周左右的时间里，
there are many, many emails.
有很多很多电子邮件。
I think I receive about six
我想我收到了大约六个
or seven hundred applications
或七百个申请
for the projects. So actually,
对于项目。所以实际上，
I'm overwhelmed with the email for the past
我对过去的电子邮件感到不知所措
few weeks. So for those
几周。所以对于那些
students, if you write in
同学们，如果你写
during this period and if I do not
在此期间，如果我不这样做
respond, please try to be understanding
回复，请尽量理解
because there are just too many
因为太多了
email applications for the
电子邮件申请
projects for the past one week or so.
过去一周左右的项目。
Okay, but moving forward, yeah,
好吧，但继续前进，是的，
when you write in, I'll definitely respond to you.
当你写信的时候，我一定会回复你。
Okay, so this is the
好的，这就是
course outline for
课程大纲
this particular course. So it's divided
这门特殊的课程。所以就分了
into six parts. So
分为六个部分。所以
first of all, the first thing we are going to look at
首先，我们首先要看的是
is the introduction and basics.
是介绍和基础知识。
Before I continue, can I just check
在继续之前，我可以检查一下吗
the students at the back? Can you all hear me?
后面的学生呢？你们都能听到我说话吗？
Okay, great.
好的，太好了。
Okay, and then
好吧，然后
part two, we are going to look at image
第二部分，我们将看图像
compression and JPEG standard.
压缩和 JPEG 标准。
Okay, and then part three, we'll be looking
好的，然后第三部分，我们会寻找
at video compression and standards.
视频压缩和标准。
And then afterwards, part four
然后是第四部分
we'll be moving on to some AI
我们将继续讨论一些人工智能
models and architectures.
模型和架构。
Okay, and then part five, we'll be
好的，然后第五部分，我们会
looking at some video analysis
看一些视频分析
and understanding. And then finally,
和理解。最后，
part six, we'll be looking at some emerging
第六部分，我们将关注一些新兴的
topics and image and video processing.
主题以及图像和视频处理。
So that's a general overview
这是一般概述
of the course.
当然。
So you can see pretty much
所以你可以看到很多
the earlier part tends to be
前面的部分往往是
more focusing on
更专注于
compression, so video
压缩，所以视频
compression. And the
压缩。还有
second half of the
的后半段
course tends to be more on
当然更倾向于
AI and then the video analytics.
人工智能，然后是视频分析。
So these are the two
所以这是两个
key focus for this particular
这个特定的重点
course.
课程。
Okay, so for this course, there are
好的，对于本课程，有
some references. Of course, nowadays
一些参考资料。当然，如今
you can make use of different
你可以利用不同的
tools to help you to do the learning.
帮助您进行学习的工具。
You should try to make use
你应该尝试利用
of all the tools, which include, for example,
所有工具，其中包括，例如，
usual ones like Google's.
常见的比如谷歌的。
You should also use the
您还应该使用
chat.gbt and other
聊天.gbt 和其他
resources like Quora and
Quora 等资源
also some traditional textbooks.
还有一些传统的教科书。
So by all means, if you have any
所以无论如何，如果你有的话
questions regarding the course,
有关课程的问题，
make use of all the resources out there
利用所有的资源
to help you to do the learning.
帮助您完成学习。
But of course, if you are using tools
但当然，如果您使用工具
like chat.gbt, you have to be
就像chat.gbt一样，你必须是
a little bit more careful because the content
稍微小心一点，因为内容
that's being presented may not
所呈现的内容可能不会
be 100% accurate.
100%准确。
Right, okay, so this slide is the
好的，好的，这张幻灯片就是
standard slide that the school actually
学校实际上的标准幻灯片
suggests us to include, which is just to
建议我们包括，这只是为了
remind you that the materials
提醒您，材料
in the slides are copyrighted by
幻灯片中的版权归
respective publishers and authors.
各自的出版商和作者。
And the slides should only be
幻灯片应该只
used for your own personal studies.
用于您自己的个人研究。
So no
所以不
part of the slides should be recorded, reproduced
部分幻灯片应被记录、复制
or distributed without the
或未经分发
permission of the author.
作者的许可。
So the reason why we have this is that
所以我们有这个的原因是
I mean for some of you, probably you already
我的意思是对于你们中的一些人来说，可能你们已经
know, right,
知道，对，
there are some students who actually
有一些学生实际上
go and record
去记录
the material and then afterwards sell
材料然后出售
it online. Right? There are some
它在线。正确的？有一些
websites like Course Hero,
诸如课程英雄之类的网站，
actually you can find the lecture notes,
其实你可以找到讲义，
the exercises, the
练习，
assignment as well as the solution online.
作业以及在线解答。
So therefore we do not encourage
因此我们不鼓励
you all to record it.
大家来记录一下吧。
So it's to stop that.
所以要阻止这种情况。
Okay.
好的。
Right, so for many of you,
是的，所以对于你们很多人来说，
this is probably one of the most
这可能是最重要的之一
important things you would like to look at for
您想要查看的重要内容
a course. So for this course, in terms
一门课程。所以对于本课程而言
of the assessment, it's pretty
评价来说，还是蛮漂亮的
standard throughout for
标准贯穿始终
MSc courses. So the
理学硕士课程。所以
first component is examination.
第一个组成部分是考试。
So examination will account for
所以考试会考虑
60%.
60%。
So it consists of
所以它包括
four questions. So you have to answer
四个问题。所以你必须回答
all the four questions and
所有四个问题以及
it will be closed book. Okay? So it's a
这将是封闭的书。好的？所以这是一个
closed book examination at the end
闭卷考试结束
of the semester.
学期的。
In addition to that, there's also
除此之外，还有
this continuous assessment.
这种持续的评估。
So continuous assessment is 40%.
所以持续考核是40%。
It will consist of
它将包括
two CA. So the first
两个CA。所以第一个
one is homework assignment.
一是家庭作业。
So this homework assignment, I plan to
所以这个作业我打算
release it around week five
第五周左右发布
or week six around that time.
或大约在那个时候的第六周。
So it will be a homework assignment
所以这将是一项家庭作业
which is 20%.
即 20%。
And the second component is
第二个组成部分是
quiz, which will account for
测验，这将说明
another 20%. So this
另外20%。所以这个
quiz will likely occur around
测验可能会发生在
week 11 or week 12.
第 11 周或第 12 周。
So once it's a little bit closer,
所以一旦距离稍微近一点
I will inform you regarding the quiz
我会通知您有关测验的信息
arrangement.
安排。
So far, are there any questions?
到目前为止，还有什么问题吗？
Do you hear any echo?
你听到任何回声吗？
The sound quality is okay.
音质还可以。
Okay, so next
好的，那么接下来
we'll move on to part one on the
我们将继续讨论第一部分
introduction of this
对此的介绍
course here. So this, today's
当然在这里。那么今天这个
lecture is pretty much on introduction
讲座主要是介绍
so you can more like sit back and relax.
这样您就可以更加高枕无忧。
Yeah, and then after
是的，然后之后
the introduction, then we'll formally move into
介绍完了，接下来我们就正式进入
the more technical part
更具技术性的部分
of the course. But the first part
当然。但第一部分
will be mainly on introduction
将以介绍为主
and basics.
和基础知识。
Right, so in part one, these
是的，所以在第一部分中，这些
are the topics we are going to cover. So
是我们要讨论的主题。所以
first of all, we are going to introduce
首先我们要介绍的是
the basic concept about image
图像的基本概念
and video. So what are actually images
和视频。那么图像到底是什么
and videos? And then we'll be looking
和视频？然后我们会寻找
at some selected different topics
在一些选定的不同主题
of video signal processing and application.
视频信号处理及应用.
Because if you think about
因为如果你想
video, right, video signal
视频，右，视频信号
processing, actually the title itself is very
处理，其实标题本身就很
broad. It can cover many,
广阔。可以涵盖很多，
many different aspects of video signal
视频信号的许多不同方面
processing. It's a very broad
加工。这是一个非常广泛的
topic. But as I
话题。但正如我
mentioned, for this particular course
提到，对于这个特定的课程
there will be two key focus that we'll be
我们将有两个重点
focusing on. One is the coding
专注于.一是编码
and compression, okay, and communication.
和压缩，好吧，还有沟通。
The second one is on
第二个已开启
the analysis and analytics
分析与分析
and understanding. So these are the
和理解。所以这些是
two key focus for
两个关键焦点
this particular course here.
这门特殊的课程在这里。
Okay, so in the first part,
好的，所以在第一部分中，
as I mentioned, the first
正如我提到的，第一个
important part will be on the
重要的部分将在
image and video standard. So
图像和视频标准。所以
we'll be talking about different types
我们将讨论不同类型
of compression, such as
的压缩，例如
we'll start off with image compression,
我们将从图像压缩开始，
and afterwards we'll move on to video
然后我们将继续观看视频
compression. So in the process
压缩。所以在这个过程中
of introducing this compression
引入这种压缩
techniques, we'll also introduce
技术，我们还将介绍
some standards that you
你认为的一些标准
probably have heard of, such as
可能听说过，比如
JPEG image compression,
JPEG图像压缩，
video compression, you probably heard about
视频压缩，您可能听说过
MPEG as well as H.26x
MPEG 以及 H.26x
series of compression.
系列压缩。
So those are the topics
所以这些就是主题
we're going to cover in the first
我们将在第一部分介绍
part of the course.
课程的一部分。
Afterwards we'll move on to the second part,
接下来我们将进入第二部分，
where we'll be talking about video
我们将在这里讨论视频
analysis and understanding.
分析和理解。
So in order to do that, we'll try to introduce
因此，为了做到这一点，我们将尝试引入
some AI models.
一些人工智能模型。
So we'll first of all try to cover
所以我们首先要尝试涵盖
concepts such as linear classifier,
线性分类器等概念，
convolutional
卷积的
neural network, recurrent neural
神经网络、循环神经网络
network, LSTM,
网络、LSTM、
and then transformer, and then probably
然后变压器，然后可能
some of the relevant concepts.
一些相关的概念。
So we'll try to introduce those basic
所以我们将尝试介绍这些基本的
AI models first, and afterwards we'll
首先进行人工智能模型，然后我们将
proceed to look at some sample video
继续观看一些示例视频
analytics application,
分析应用程序，
such as object
比如物体
detection, multiple object
检测，多个物体
tracking, post estimation,
跟踪、事后估计、
action recognition in
动作识别
videos. So those are the topics we'll cover.
视频。这些就是我们将要讨论的主题。
And then finally, under the
最后，在
emerging topics, we'll try
新兴主题，我们会尝试
to cover some recent trends.
涵盖一些最近的趋势。
So specifically, we'll
那么具体来说，我们将
probably be talking about some large language
可能正在谈论一些大型语言
model, and also some
模型，还有一些
foundation models, in the
基础模型，在
context of video analytics.
视频分析的背景。
So that's a general overview
这是一般概述
of this particular course here.
这门特殊课程的介绍在这里。
So first,
所以首先，
let's look at the image and video
让我们看一下图片和视频
basics.
基础知识。
So what is an image? I think most of you
那么什么是图像呢？我想你们大多数人
should be familiar with image
应该熟悉图像
already. So an image is nothing
已经。所以图像什么都不是
but if you think about it, it's actually a two-dimensional
但如果你仔细想想，它实际上是一个二维的
array, or a matrix
数组，或矩阵
of pixel elements.
像素元素。
So you have a two-dimensional array
所以你有一个二维数组
of small elements here.
这里的小元素。
So each of the smallest elements is
所以每个最小的元素是
known as a pixel. So pixels stand
称为像素。所以像素站
for picture element.
对于图片元素。
So image is an important media
所以形象是一个重要的媒体
for us to convey the information.
以便我们传达信息。
So we need to store it,
所以我们需要存储它，
we need to process, and we need to present
我们需要处理，我们需要呈现
it. So that's the basic
它。这就是基本的
understanding of what an image is.
了解图像是什么。
So it's represented by a two-dimensional
所以用二维表示
matrix, or
矩阵，或
two-dimensional array of pixels here.
这里是二维像素数组。
So for example, you can see this is an
例如，您可以看到这是一个
image. So this image
图像。所以这个图像
consists of different rows
由不同的行组成
of pixels here.
这里的像素数。
So each of the basic elements is a pixel.
所以每个基本元素都是一个像素。
So there are many
所以有很多
different popular image formats,
不同流行的图像格式，
such as JPEG,
例如 JPEG、
which stands for Joint Photographic Expert Group,
代表联合摄影专家组，
and then
进而
TIFF, TAC, Image File Format,
TIFF、TAC、图像文件格式、
BMP, Bitmap Format, and so on.
BMP、位图格式等。
So for this course, we'll spend
所以对于本课程，我们将花费
some time to talk about
有时间谈谈
the techniques for image compression,
图像压缩技术，
as well as the underlying principle
以及基本原则
for JPEG image compression.
用于 JPEG 图像压缩。
So that's
所以那就是
the basic
基本的
parts regarding the image
关于图像的部分
compression that we're going to study.
我们要研究的压缩。
And then before
然后之前
we continue, as I mentioned
正如我提到的，我们继续
for this lecture, we are going to
对于本次讲座，我们将
talk about some of the basics to
谈谈一些基础知识
make sure that everyone has a common understanding
确保每个人都有共同的理解
and is familiar with
并且熟悉
the terms that we are using.
我们正在使用的术语。
So first of all, we're going
所以首先我们要
to introduce the concept of pixels and resolution.
介绍像素和分辨率的概念。
So I believe everyone
所以我相信大家
should understand what a pixel is.
应该明白什么是像素。
So pixels
所以像素
represent picture elements.
代表图片元素。
So it's the smallest element in
所以它是最小的元素
a digital image. So if you look
数字图像。所以如果你看
at this particular image here,
在这个特定的图像中，
it consists of a two-dimensional
它由一个二维的
array or matrix of
的数组或矩阵
pixels.
像素。
So if you zoom in
所以如果你放大
these parts of the image, if you zoom in
如果放大图像的这些部分
in, then you can see each of these
然后你就可以看到其中的每一个
pixels a lot more clearly.
像素更清晰。
So each of these particular elements here
所以这里的每一个特定元素
is known as a pixel, which is
被称为像素，即
the picture element.
图片元素。
So another associated
所以另一个关联
concept with image
概念与图像
is resolution. So what is the meaning
是分辨率。那么意义何在
of resolution? Resolution means the number
分辨率？分辨率是指数量
of pixels in the image. So there's
图像中的像素数。所以有
a few different ways you can express
几种不同的表达方式
the number of pixels in the image.
图像中的像素数。
You can simply express
你可以简单地表达
it in terms of the total pixel count.
就总像素数而言。
For example, you can say that this particular
例如，您可以说这个特定的
image is 10 megapixel.
图像为 10 兆像素。
That means this image actually
这意味着这张图片实际上
consists of 10 megapixels
由10兆像素组成
of pixels. Or it
像素。或者它
can be expressed as width times
可以表示为宽度乘以
height. For example,
高度。例如，
for first
首先
total pixel count, for example, if you say an image
总像素数，例如，如果您说图像
can be 5 megapixels.
可以是5兆像素。
In terms of, you can
就而言，你可以
also express it as width times height.
也将其表示为宽度乘以高度。
An example is 640 by
一个例子是 640
480. So what it means is that
480.所以这意味着
you have the number, the row
你有数字，行
is 640 and the height
是640，高度
is 480.
是 480。
So this is the dimension of your image.
这就是你的图像的尺寸。
Another way of
另一种方式
expressing this resolution
表达本决议
in the context of printing and
在印刷和
scanning is this pixel
扫描的是这个像素
per inch, or PPI.
每英寸，或 PPI。
So for example, when you say that you are trying
例如，当你说你正在尝试时
to print a certain document, you need
要打印某个文档，您需要
to indicate how many pixels per inch.
表示每英寸有多少个像素。
In one inch of space,
一英寸的空间里，
how many pixels can you squeeze it?
你能压缩多少像素？
So these are different ways for you
所以这些对你来说是不同的方式
to express the resolution.
来表达决心。
So you can see this resolution
所以你可以看到这个分辨率
pretty much is trying to reflect
几乎是在试图反映
the ability for you
适合你的能力
to distinguish or
来区分或
differentiate fine details in an image.
区分图像中的精细细节。
So if you look at this small image and you
所以如果你看这张小图片并且你
zoom it in, clearly, if
放大它，清楚地，如果
you have a higher resolution, that means
你有更高的分辨率，这意味着
you can pack more information into it.
您可以将更多信息放入其中。
That means you will be able to see a lot more details.
这意味着您将能够看到更多详细信息。
So that is the
所以这就是
basic idea of resolution.
决议的基本思想。
So the next term that we are going to introduce
所以我们要介绍的下一个术语
is bit depth or color depth.
是位深度或颜色深度。
So what is bit depth and color depth?
那么什么是位深度和颜色深度呢？
So bit depth or color depth is the number
所以位深度或颜色深度就是数字
of bits used to represent
用于表示的位数
each pixel.
每个像素。
So if you look at these images
所以如果你看这些图片
here, there are three types of images
这里有三种类型的图像
here. So the first one is a binary
这里。所以第一个是二进制的
image.
图像。
So you can see binary image because it consists of
所以你可以看到二值图像，因为它由
either, you know, the color can
要么，你知道，颜色可以
only be either black or
只能是黑色或
white. So if it's black or white,
白色的。所以无论是黑色还是白色
that means how many bits do you
这意味着你有多少位
need to represent it?
需要代表吗？
If it's for a binary
如果是二进制文件
image, it only can have
图像，它只能有
two colors, which is either black or white.
两种颜色，即黑色或白色。
So if it's either black or white, how many
那么如果它是黑色或白色，有多少
bits do you need to represent each pixel?
您需要表示每个像素的位吗？
One,
一，
because it can only have two possible values.
因为它只能有两个可能的值。
So therefore, for binary images
因此，对于二值图像
like this, you only need to have one bit
像这样，你只需要一点
represented, okay? Because it's either
代表，好吗？因为它要么是
black or white.
黑色或白色。
So the next time is a grayscale images.
所以接下来的时间是灰度图像。
So these are examples of grayscale
这些是灰度的例子
images. So these are probably like
图像。所以这些可能就像
your grandparents' generations of
你的祖父母辈
photos or my
照片或我的
mother's generation of photos.
母亲一代的照片。
So these are the grayscale images here.
这些是这里的灰度图像。
So very often, we use
所以很多时候我们会使用
eight bits represented.
表示八位。
So if we use eight bits to represent it,
所以如果我们用八位来表示它，
that means how many possible
这意味着有多少种可能
gray levels or tones can
灰度级或色调可以
it show?
它显示？
For each pixel?
对于每个像素？
Sorry?
对不起？
256,
256、
so it's two to the power of eight
所以它是二的八次方
because for each bit
因为对于每一位
you can have two possible values. So two
你可以有两个可能的值。那么两个
times two times two, you times it
乘以二乘以二，你乘以它
eight times, then it's two to the power of eight,
八次，那么就是二的八次方，
which is 256
这是 256
possible gray
可能的灰色
level. So this is a
等级。所以这是一个
this image here is an example
这张图片是一个例子
of grayscale images here.
此处的灰度图像。
And if you zoom in this more
如果你再放大一点
pixel blocks here,
这里的像素块，
you can see this is the examples of grayscale
你可以看到这是灰度的例子
images. For grayscale
图像。对于灰度
images and binary image, it
图像和二值图像，它
only consists of one channel
仅由一个通道组成
or one component.
或一个组件。
So for this binary
所以对于这个二进制文件
or grayscale image, it only has
或灰度图像，它只有
one channel
一个通道
or one component.
或一个组件。
So and then for each component,
那么对于每个组件，
if you zoom it in, just now
如果你放大它，就现在
we already know if we use eight bits
我们已经知道是否使用八位
to represent it, that means you can have
代表它，这意味着你可以有
256 gray
256灰色
level. So this 256
等级。所以这个256
gray level typically we represent
我们通常代表的灰度级
from zero to 255.
从零到 255。
So zero to 255.
所以从 0 到 255。
And if it's smaller, if the
如果它更小，如果
value is smaller, that means it's darker.
值越小，表示颜色越暗。
If the value is larger, that means
如果该值较大，则意味着
it's brighter. So you can see for example,
它更亮了。所以你可以看到，例如，
for smaller value
对于较小的值
each byte 51 here is actually
这里的每个字节51实际上是
corresponds to darker pixel.
对应于较暗的像素。
And if the value is larger such as
如果该值较大，例如
177,
177、
it corresponds to brighter pixel.
它对应于更亮的像素。
So that's the
这就是
basic understanding.
基本了解。
So the next types of image that we have
所以我们接下来的图像类型
is color images. So this color image
是彩色图像。所以这个彩色图像
is very common. That's what we see every
很常见。这就是我们每一次看到的
day. So this is an example
天。这是一个例子
of the color image.
的彩色图像。
So if you look at this particular
所以如果你看看这个特定的
color image, again it consists of
彩色图像，同样它由以下组成
different pixels here.
这里有不同的像素。
Each of these is actually a
其中每一个实际上都是一个
pixel. And each of
像素。并且每一个
this pixel will consist of a triplet
该像素将由一个三元组组成
of value. That means it has three values
的价值。这意味着它具有三个值
here. Triplets of value. So each
这里。价值三元组。所以每个
of these pixels here would have red,
这里的这些像素将是红色的，
green and blue. So for example,
绿色和蓝色。例如，
these pixels here will consist of
这里的这些像素将包括
red, green and blue. So it has three
红色、绿色和蓝色。所以它有三个
channels. So red,
渠道。那么红，
green and blue are referred
绿色和蓝色被引用
to as three channels or
作为三个通道或
three components.
三个组成部分。
So typically,
所以通常情况下，
because each of these
因为这些中的每一个
channels or components,
通道或组件，
we use eight bits to represent it.
我们用八位来表示它。
So therefore, each pixel now
因此，现在每个像素
can be represented as three times
可以表示为三倍
eight, which is 24 bits.
八位，即 24 位。
So that is the
所以这就是
basic visualizations
基本可视化
of how we represent different
我们如何代表不同
types of images.
图像类型。
So the next thing we are going to
所以接下来我们要做的就是
look at is some
看看有一些
column color
列颜色
spaces. So what are color
空间。那么什么是颜色
spaces? So just now, the color
空格？所以刚才的颜色
image that we've shown, we know that
我们已经展示的图像，我们知道
color image, again, consists
彩色图像再次由
of a two-dimensional array or
二维数组或
matrix of pixels. And for each
像素矩阵。并且对于每个
pixel, it can be shown
像素，可以显示
as triplets of value.
作为价值的三元组。
The example that was shown is red,
显示的示例是红色的，
green and blue. RGB.
绿色和蓝色。 RGB。
But this particular way of representing
但这种特殊的表示方式
the color image is not
彩色图像不是
the only way. So there are actually
唯一的办法。所以实际上有
many different ways you can represent
您可以用多种不同的方式来表示
color images. So different
彩色图像。如此不同
ways of representing color images
表示彩色图像的方法
are known as color
被称为颜色
spaces or color model.
空间或颜色模型。
So there's many different ways
所以有很多不同的方法
you can represent colors,
你可以代表颜色，
images.
图像。
And this is known as color spaces.
这就是所谓的色彩空间。
So this particular figure
所以这个特定的数字
shows some of the examples.
显示了一些示例。
For example, red, green, blue is one
例如，红、绿、蓝是其中之一
common color space.
共同的色彩空间。
HSI hue saturation
HSI 色调饱和度
intensity is another common
强度是另一个常见的
color space. And later on,
色彩空间。后来，
you're going to see why CBCR
你就会明白为什么 CBCR
is also another common color
也是另一种常见的颜色
space. We are going to
空间。我们要去
look at each of these color spaces
查看每个色彩空间
and also talk about why,
并谈谈原因，
in some cases, we want to use this color
在某些情况下，我们想使用这种颜色
space, and in some cases, we use
空间，在某些情况下，我们使用
another color space.
另一个色彩空间。
So let's try to look at,
那么让我们试着看看，
first of all, color
首先，颜色
images again. So color images
再次图像。所以彩色图像
can be expressed in terms of different color
可以用不同的颜色来表达
spaces, as I mentioned. There's many different
正如我提到的，空格。有很多不同的
ways you can express the color.
表达颜色的方式。
So some of the common color space
那么一些常见的色彩空间
is RGB. For example,
是RGB。例如，
the image that we have just now earlier on
我们刚才看到的图像
shown is RGB images.
显示的是 RGB 图像。
HSI is another popular
恒生指数是另一个受欢迎的指数
one, and why CBCR
一、为什么 CBCR
is another popular one. So this
是另一种流行的。所以这个
why CBCR color space is
为什么 CBCR 色彩空间是
commonly used in standards
标准中常用的
such as image and video
例如图像和视频
compression and TV transmission.
压缩和电视传输。
So these are the color space that's commonly
这些是常见的色彩空间
used in those applications
在这些应用程序中使用
here. So if you look at RGB
这里。所以如果你看一下 RGB
color space, you can see
色彩空间，你可以看到
the color is represented by
颜色表示为
triplets. Now we say each pixel has three
三胞胎。现在我们说每个像素有三个
values. So these three values
价值观。所以这三个值
are triplets of value as
值的三元组为
red, green and blue, RGB.
红、绿、蓝，RGB。
So if you look at
所以如果你看
this particular
这个特定的
color model
色彩模型
here, I think this is some color
在这里，我想这是某种颜色
model that you probably, for most students,
对于大多数学生来说，你可能会认为，
you study in secondary school.
你在中学学习。
So you have the primary color,
所以你有原色，
which is red,
是红色的，
green and blue. So if you
绿色和蓝色。所以如果你
add red and green, you'll
添加红色和绿色，你会
get yellow, red and blue you'll get
得到黄色，红色和蓝色你会得到
magenta, and then green
洋红色，然后绿色
and blue you'll get cyan. And if
和蓝色你会得到青色。如果
you add these three colors, you'll get a white
你添加这三种颜色，你会得到白色
color. So this is the standard
颜色。所以这是标准
additive color model
加色模型
that you study in secondary school.
你在中学学习。
So another
那么另一个
visualizations of this particular primary
这个特定初级的可视化
color, we can also visualize it in terms
颜色，我们也可以用术语来形象化它
of a color cube. So we visualize
的颜色立方体。所以我们想象
it in the color cube, then red,
它在颜色立方体中，然后是红色，
this axis is red,
该轴是红色的，
this axis is green, and
该轴是绿色的，并且
this axis is blue here.
该轴在这里是蓝色的。
So red will take the values of
所以红色将取以下值
1, 0, 0.
1, 0, 0。
Green is 0, 1, 0.
绿色是 0, 1, 0。
And blue is 0, 0, 1.
蓝色是 0, 0, 1。
So it's like the unit values along
所以就像单位值一样
this axis here.
这个轴在这里。
And then as we have seen,
然后正如我们所看到的，
red plus green will give you yellow.
红色加绿色会得到黄色。
So this corner will be yellow.
所以这个角会是黄色的。
Red and blue
红色和蓝色
will be magenta. This corner will be
将是洋红色。这个角落将会是
magenta, and blue and green,
洋红色、蓝色和绿色，
this corner will be cyan.
这个角将是青色的。
And if you add up these three colors, then this
如果你把这三种颜色加起来，那就是
particular diagonal, the corner
特定的对角线、角
will be the white color. So
将是白色。所以
this particular corner will be
这个特定的角落将是
white color, and if the value is
白色，如果值为
0, 0, 0, then it's black color.
0, 0, 0，那么它是黑色。
So if you draw a line to connect
所以如果你画一条线来连接
the black to the white, this
从黑到白，这个
will correspond to the grayscale
将对应于灰度
representation.
表示。
So this is the representation
所以这就是代表
of the RGB color cube.
RGB 颜色立方体。
So a little bit more
所以再多一点
about the RGB
关于RGB
images. So earlier on
图像。所以早些时候
we mentioned, typically we represent
我们提到，通常我们代表
as 24 bits color images.
作为 24 位彩色图像。
So if you look at this particular
所以如果你看看这个特定的
color image, you
彩色图像，你
divide into three different channels.
分为三个不同的通道。
You have the red channel, green channel,
你有红色通道，绿色通道，
and the blue channel. So an image,
和蓝色通道。所以一个图像，
typically, a color image, if you
通常是彩色图像，如果您
represent in terms of RGB color,
以 RGB 颜色表示，
images, that means there's three
图像，这意味着有三个
channels, and then each of these channels you can
频道，然后您可以
actually separate them. Then
实际上将它们分开。然后
this is what you're going to get, these three channels
这就是你将得到的，这三个频道
here. Okay, so you can
这里。好的，所以你可以
see that each pixel has three
看到每个像素有三个
components, red, green, and blue, you already know.
成分，红色，绿色和蓝色，你已经知道了。
And then for each component, for each
然后对于每个组件，对于每个
pixel, we use eight bits to represent
像素，我们用八位来表示
it. Right, so therefore
它。对，所以所以
for each channel, because we use
对于每个通道，因为我们使用
eight bits, that means it has two
八位，这意味着它有两个
56 tones,
56个音调，
and the value that it represents is
它代表的值是
from 0 to 255.
从 0 到 255。
And if the color is black,
如果颜色是黑色，
it's 000, and it's white,
它是 000，它是白色的，
it's 255, 255,
是 255、 255、
255, in terms of the
255、就
color representation.
颜色表示。
And also, if you look at this
而且，如果你看看这个
particular image, if you break it into the
特定的图像，如果你把它分解成
three channels, you can see
三个频道，你可以看到
for example this red channel here,
例如这里的红色通道，
this area that corresponds to
该区域对应于
the red color, when you
红色，当你
look at the red channel here,
看这里的红色通道，
the value is actually
该值实际上是
brighter or whiter.
更亮或更白。
That's because how we represent this
那是因为我们如何表示这一点
color is that, as we
颜色就是这样，就像我们
have mentioned before, if the value
之前已经提到过，如果值
is larger, it's whiter
更大，更白
or it's brighter. And if the value
或者它更亮。如果值
is smaller, it's darker
越小，颜色越暗
or blacker. So therefore,
或者更黑。因此，
if you look at the red channel, because the
如果你看红色通道，因为
red channel actually reflects the red
红色通道实际上反映了红色
component, so this region
组件，所以这个区域
corresponds to the red component
对应红色分量
here. So that's why their values
这里。这就是为什么他们的价值观
are larger, and because
更大，并且因为
their values are larger, they are indicated
它们的值较大，表示
as brighter.
更明亮。
Other regions that, for example,
其他地区，例如，
doesn't contain that much red color,
不含那么多红色，
it will be
这将是
darker.
更暗。
So if you now look at the green channel,
所以如果你现在看看绿色通道
you can see these regions here contain the
你可以在这里看到这些区域包含
green channel, so that's why
绿色通道，所以这就是为什么
their value is larger and
它们的价值更大并且
hence a little bit brighter.
因此稍微亮一点。
And then finally, for this particular
最后，对于这个特殊的
image, you can see because there's hardly any
图片，你可以看到，因为几乎没有
blue component, so therefore
蓝色分量，因此
if you look at the blue channel, most of them
如果你看蓝色通道，大多数
are dark, which indicate
是黑色的，这表明
that their value is very small,
它们的价值非常小，
that means not much blue component.
这意味着蓝色成分不多。
Okay, so just now we have introduced
好的，刚才我们已经介绍了
one very common color space,
一种非常常见的色彩空间，
which is RGB color space.
这是RGB色彩空间。
So the next class of color
所以下一类颜色
space that we are going to
我们要去的空间
show is the YUV,
显示的是YUV，
YIQ and YCBCR color space.
YIQ 和 YCBCR 色彩空间。
So this
所以这个
color space is another scheme
色彩空间是另一种方案
to represent color images.
来表示彩色图像。
So for this particular color
所以对于这种特殊的颜色
images, that means actually the images
图像，这实际上意味着图像
will be represented by three different
将由三个不同的代表
channels again. But this
再次频道。但这
three different channels now will be
现在将有三个不同的渠道
the Y channel, if you look
Y 通道，如果你看的话
at this YUV
在这个YUV
channel, that means this three channel will be
通道，这意味着这三个通道将是
represented by Y channel,
由Y通道表示，
U channel and V channel
U通道和V通道
now. So this is another
现在。所以这是另一个
way of representing
表示方式
the color image.
彩色图像。
And YIQ and YCBCR
还有 YIQ 和 YCBCR
are actually just a very
实际上只是一个非常
similar to YUV,
与YUV类似，
they are just a small variation, slightly
它们只是一个小的变化，稍微
different.
不同的。
So pretty much, as I've
非常多，正如我所经历的那样
already explained, YIQ
已经解释过了，YIQ
and YCBCR
和YCBCR
are small variations of
是小的变化
YUV channel, color
YUV通道、颜色
space. Therefore, typically we consider
空间。因此，通常我们考虑
them as more or less the same.
它们或多或少是相同的。
So among this color space,
所以在这个色彩空间中，
for example, if we use the YUV
例如，如果我们使用 YUV
as the example here,
作为这里的例子，
this Y channel corresponds
该Y通道对应
to luminance channel. So
到亮度通道。所以
luminance means the brightness part,
亮度表示亮度部分，
the black and white, the
黑与白，
brightness part.
亮度部分。
So the luminance is actually
所以亮度实际上是
the brightness part or the black and white
亮度部分或黑白
parts of the image.
图像的部分。
And then the UV actually
然后实际上是紫外线
corresponds to the chrominance part.
对应色度部分。
So this UV refers to the
所以这个UV指的是
chrominance part. So chrominance
色度部分。所以色度
means it's the color part of the image.
意味着它是图像的颜色部分。
Okay, color part of the
好的，给部分颜色上色
image.
图像。
So, this,
所以，这个，
why do we want to, in some cases,
为什么在某些情况下我们想要
represent an image or
代表一个图像或
video in terms of YUV,
以 YUV 表示的视频，
YIQ or YCBCR
YIQ 或 YCBCR
color space? For example,
色彩空间？例如，
in video broadcasting,
在视频广播中，
typically we use these types
通常我们使用这些类型
of color space, YUV,
色彩空间，YUV，
YIQ,
益智商,
and for JPEG and image,
对于 JPEG 和图像，
JPEG and
JPEG 和
MPEG compression, we use YCBCR.
MPEG压缩，我们使用YCBCR。
So why do we want
那么我们为什么要
to use this kind of color space
使用这种颜色空间
in video broadcasting
在视频广播中
or
或者
compression? So here the
压缩？所以这里的
answer is, it makes good
答案是，这很好
use of the bandwidth. But what exactly
带宽的使用。但到底是什么
does that mean?
这是什么意思？
Okay.
好的。
I mean, for example, in
我的意思是，例如，在
this
这
video broadcasting,
视频广播、
you can choose to represent
你可以选择代表
your image and video as RGB.
您的图像和视频为 RGB。
But if you do that,
但如果你这样做的话
when you want to do the transmission,
当你想要进行传输时，
it's not so efficient.
它不是那么有效。
As compared to if you decided
与如果你决定相比
to change this color space
改变这个色彩空间
from RGB to
从 RGB 到
YCBCR or
YCBCR 或
YUV color space.
YUV 色彩空间。
So when you represent the image and
所以当你代表图像并且
video using YUV
使用 YUV 的视频
color space, and then when you do
色彩空间，然后当你这样做时
the transmission,
传输，
we can do it in a more efficient
我们可以更有效地做到这一点
manner. So anyone
方式。所以任何人
has any idea why is that the case?
知道为什么会这样吗？
Yes.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So,
所以，
yeah, what
是的，什么
you're trying to explain is more
你试图解释的是更多
like the temporal
就像暂时的
correlation.
相关性。
Okay, the similarity
好吧，相似度
across different frames,
跨越不同的框架，
yeah, when you're trying to
是的，当你试图
do the transmission.
进行传输。
Okay, so in the context of
好的，所以在上下文中
compression, because each
压缩，因为每个
frames, okay, consecutive frames
帧，好的，连续帧
are very similar, so you
非常相似，所以你
only need to encode the small difference.
只需要对微小的差异进行编码。
I believe that's what you are coming from.
我相信这就是你的出身。
But still, it does not
但仍然没有
clearly explain what's the difference.
清楚地解释有什么区别。
Why? I mean, for,
为什么？我的意思是，为了，
if you represent the image as RGB
如果将图像表示为 RGB
or YCBCR,
或YCBCR，
okay, now I mean both of them,
好吧，现在我指的是他们两个，
you can also
你也可以
leverage on the similarity
利用相似性
or the inter-frame
或帧间
correlation for you to help to perform
相关性可以帮助您执行
the compression. But it still
压缩。但它仍然
doesn't really quite explain why
并没有真正解释为什么
one color space is better
一种颜色空间更好
than the other color space.
比其他色彩空间。
Any other
任何其他
thought?
想法？
Okay, so one of the reasons why in
好的，原因之一是
the context of video transmission,
视频传输的背景下，
okay, compression and then
好的，压缩然后
TV transmissions, why we
电视传输，为什么我们
want to represent the color in these
想要代表这些颜色
types of YCBCR color spaces,
YCBCR 色彩空间的类型，
is that once we convert
一旦我们转换
the color space from RGB
来自 RGB 的色彩空间
into this YCBCR,
进入这个YCBCR，
YUV color space,
YUV色彩空间，
for example, this white part
例如这个白色部分
just now we mentioned, it corresponds to
刚才我们提到的，它对应的是
the luminance part,
亮度部分，
which is the brightness component.
这是亮度分量。
And this UV corresponds
而这个UV对应的是
to the chrominance part, which is the
到色度部分，即
color component. So the next
颜色成分。那么接下来
thing that you need to know is the
你需要知道的是
how human viscous system works.
人体粘性系统如何工作。
Our human viscous systems
我们的人体粘性系统
are, right in our eye, there's actually
是，就在我们的眼中，实际上有
two types of cell, rot and cone.
两种类型的细胞，腐烂细胞和圆锥细胞。
Probably if you
也许如果你
can still remember what you
仍然记得你的事
study in the secondary school biology.
学习中学生物学。
You know our human eye,
你知道我们人眼，
the retina, actually has
视网膜，实际上有
two types of
两种类型的
this light
这光
kind of sensitive cell that
一种敏感细胞
can perceive the light. One is a rot,
可以感知光。一个是腐烂，
the other is a cone.
另一个是圆锥体。
So one of them is sensitive to
所以其中之一是敏感的
the color component,
颜色分量，
the other is sensitive to the brightness
另一个对亮度敏感
component. That's why
成分。这就是为什么
in the
在
middle of the night,
半夜，
if you wake up and when you go to the
如果你醒来并且当你去
toilet, actually what you can see
厕所，其实就是你所看到的
is a gray color. You cannot
是灰色的。你不能
see the color, but you can see only the
看到颜色，但只能看到
grayscale, the brightness.
灰度，亮度。
That's because our eyes are more sensitive
那是因为我们的眼睛比较敏感
to the luminance
到亮度
component. So all in all,
成分。所以总而言之，
what I'm trying to say is that for human
我想说的是对于人类来说
viscous system, actually our eye is
粘性系统，实际上我们的眼睛是
more sensitive to the luminance component
对亮度分量更敏感
as compared to the
相比于
chrominance component, or the color
色度分量，或颜色
component. So because our eyes
成分。所以因为我们的眼睛
are more sensitive
更敏感
to the luminance component
到亮度分量
and less sensitive to the chrominance
对色度不太敏感
component, that means
组件，这意味着
we can afford to throw away
我们可以扔掉
some of the information
一些信息
in the chrominance component.
在色度分量中。
Because it makes very little difference
因为差别很小
to us. So traditionally,
对我们来说。所以传统上，
because we know that, for example,
因为我们知道，例如，
for video transmission,
用于视频传输，
it requires lots of bandwidth.
它需要大量的带宽。
So bandwidth is very expensive.
所以带宽非常昂贵。
So therefore, you want to reduce
因此，你想减少
the number of bits that you want to
您想要的位数
transmit. Okay. And then
发送。好的。进而
it's very logical now,
现在这是非常合乎逻辑的
if our eyes are more sensitive to the
如果我们的眼睛对
white channel, or white
白色通道，或白色
component, then we should keep
组件，那么我们应该保留
all the information in white. And
所有信息均为白色。和
if our eyes are less sensitive
如果我们的眼睛不那么敏感
to the chrominance component,
到色度分量，
then we can afford to throw
那么我们就可以扔掉
away some of the information, by
带走一些信息，通过
dropping away some of the pixels.
丢弃一些像素。
Okay. So therefore, in short,
好的。因此，简而言之，
what I'm trying to say is that, now,
我想说的是，现在，
if you represent your image and
如果你代表你的形象并且
video into this kind of
视频变成这种
color space, there's a very
色彩空间，有一个非常
simple strategy for you to
简单的策略让你
reduce the number of
减少数量
bits that you need to transmit over
您需要传输的位
the channel.
频道。
For example, doing
例如，做
the TV transmission. What you need to do
电视传输。你需要做什么
is keep all the white channel, drop
保留所有白色通道，丢弃
some of, or sub-sample,
一些或子样本，
or drop some of the information from your
或删除您的一些信息
chrominance component. So that's
色度分量。所以那就是
why this particular color space
为什么这个特定的色彩空间
is a lot easier for
更容易
you to decide what to do, as opposed
你来决定做什么，而不是
to RGB. So, for example,
至 RGB。所以，举例来说，
if your video is RGB,
如果您的视频是 RGB，
you cannot, no, there's no
你不能，不，没有
very clear strategy. Now, if you want
非常明确的策略。现在，如果你想要
to drop some pixel, what are the pixel
删除一些像素，该像素是什么
you want to drop, or what are the channel you want
你想要删除，或者你想要什么频道
to drop? It's not so clear cut.
下降？这不是那么明确。
Okay. So that is the reason.
好的。这就是原因。
So, because of that,
所以，正因为如此，
this color space is commonly used in TV
该色彩空间常用于电视
industry and video compression.
工业和视频压缩。
So, for example, YUV
例如，YUV
is used in this PAL and
在此 PAL 中使用并且
CCAM TV standard.
CCAM 电视标准。
YQ is used
使用YQ
in NTSC, and YCBCR
NTSC 和 YCBCR
is commonly used in JPEG and
常用于 JPEG 和
MPEG compression. So, later
MPEG 压缩。所以，后来
on, when we study about JPEG and
当我们研究 JPEG 时
MPEG compression, we'll be mainly dealing
MPEG压缩，我们主要处理
with this color space here.
这里有这个色彩空间。
And then for
然后对于
different color space, RGB,
不同的色彩空间，RGB，
and this, okay, in this particular
这个，好吧，在这个特定的情况下
table, it shows the conversion
表，它显示了转换
between RGB and YQ.
RGB 和 YQ 之间。
So, you can actually just do a simple
所以，你实际上可以做一个简单的
conversion by some matrix
通过一些矩阵转换
multiplication to convert from one
乘法从一转换
color space to another color space.
颜色空间到另一个颜色空间。
Okay. So,
好的。所以，
the next thing we want to very quickly
接下来我们想要很快
touch on is CODAC.
触及的是CODAC。
So, does
那么，
any one of you know what this company
你们中的任何一个人都知道这家公司是什么
is, CODAC?
是，CODAC？
Anyone
任何人
know CODAC?
知道科达克吗？
Camera.
相机。
Okay, long time ago, right? What you heard is
好吧，很久以前了，对吧？你听到的是
long time ago. Actually, I still remember
很久以前。其实我还记得
when I was a young kid,
当我还是个小孩子的时候
my brother bought
我哥哥买了
the first kind of camera.
第一种相机。
Yeah. So, at the time, I was very
是的。所以，当时我非常
excited. You have to take this
兴奋的。你必须接受这个
camera, and then you actually have to
相机，然后你实际上必须
think very carefully exactly
仔细思考
what is the photo you want to capture.
您想要拍摄什么照片。
Because every photo, once you click it,
因为每张照片，一旦你点击它，
you capture it. It's already
你捕捉到它。已经是
one film that's been
曾经的一部电影
taken already. So,
已经采取了。所以，
it's very expensive, it's very precious.
它非常昂贵，非常珍贵。
Unlike nowadays, when you have
与现在不同的是，当你拥有
mobile phone, you can just keep taking photo.
手机就可以继续拍照。
You don't like, you just delete. But in the past,
你不喜欢就删掉吧但在过去，
the photos are actually
这些照片实际上是
using this kind of
使用这种
camera is using from
相机正在使用
this kind of
这种
analog film for you to take
模拟胶片供您拍摄
the photo. So, this company,
照片。那么，这家公司，
CODAC, used to be a very big
CODAC，曾经是一个非常大的
company, very, very important. When people talk about
公司，非常非常重要。当人们谈论
camera, they just think of CODAC.
相机，他们只想到CODAC。
So, it's just a very big
所以，这只是一个非常大的
company. So, in
公司。所以，在
the past, it's actually very dominant.
过去，它实际上非常占主导地位。
But, later
但是，后来
on, because they make
上，因为他们使
lots of money from this firm,
从这家公司赚了很多钱
analog firm that you have. But
你拥有的模拟公司。但
later on, when time starts to change,
后来，当时间开始改变时，
this digital photography
这个数码摄影
and digital camera
和数码相机
and filming start to appear, actually
实际上，拍摄开始出现
CODAC is
科达克是
very resistant to
非常抵抗
changing.
改变。
The reason is quite straightforward,
原因很简单，
because they are making so much money from making
因为他们赚了很多钱
this firm. So, when there's a new
这家公司。所以，当有新的
technology appearing,
科技的出现，
digital camera, so they are very
数码相机，所以它们非常
resistant to
抵抗
switch from analog camera to digital
从模拟相机切换到数字相机
camera. Whereas,
相机。然而，
other companies such as
其他公司，例如
Fuji, actually they manage
富士，实际上他们管理
to do the transition much
做很多过渡
more quicker. So, in short, this
更快。所以，简而言之，这
particular slide is trying to show
特别的幻灯片试图展示
that sometimes you have to
有时你必须
move on with technology.
继续技术进步。
When technology changes,
当技术发生变化时，
you just have to follow. Otherwise,
你只需要跟随。否则，
you'll become obsolete.
你会变得过时。
So, this particular
那么，这个特殊的
heading here, CODAC moment,
前往这里，CODAC时刻，
so in the past, there's a very well-known
所以在过去，有一个非常知名的
advertisement. When you want to take a
广告。当你想采取
photo, we call it a CODAC
照片，我们称之为 CODAC
moment. That means you are taking a photo.
片刻。这意味着您正在拍照。
So, that's why they call it a
所以，这就是为什么他们称其为
CODAC moment. So, anyway,
科达克时刻。所以，无论如何，
CODAC kind of went bankrupt
CODAC 有点破产了
around
大约
2012, which is about
2012年，大约是
13 years ago.
13年前。
Alright, so the next thing we are going to
好的，接下来我们要做的就是
quickly do is, we are going
快点做的是，我们要去
to look at how do we capture
看看我们如何捕捉
information,
信息，
this image and video information
该图像和视频信息
from camera. So, we are going
从相机。所以，我们要去
to spend a bit of time to talk about
花一点时间谈谈
camera, how to perform
相机，如何执行
data acquisition.
数据采集​​。
Right, so in order to do that, I actually have
是的，为了做到这一点，我实际上有
a very short video to explain
一个很短的视频来解释
to you how a camera
对你来说相机如何
works, how does it capture
工作原理，它如何捕获
lights from the
灯光从
imaging source and convert it into
图像源并将其转换为
a digital image.
数字图像。
Right, okay. So, let
对了，好吧。那么，让
me just play this video for you.
我只是为你播放这个视频。
Okay, let me just do some adjustment first. This echo is very strong here.
好吧，我先做一些调整。这里的回声非常强烈。
This program contains experiments which are performed by professionals. These tests are dangerous and may involve the use of hazardous materials. They should not be performed or imitated under any circumstances.
该程序包含由专业人员进行的实验。这些测试很危险，可能涉及使用有害材料。在任何情况下都不应执行或模仿它们。
It's all about light.
一切都与光有关。
The digital camera.
数码相机。
It's revolutionized photography
它彻底改变了摄影
by transforming light into
通过将光转化为
electricity. Everything
电。一切
is there to draw in light. From
是用来画光的。从
the camera's buttons, controls
相机的按钮、控件
and dials down to the lenses.
并向下拨至镜头。
What the digital camera
数码相机是什么
does with light is what makes it
光的作用就是它的本质
so revolutionary.
如此革命性。
It turns
原来
light into electrical charges
光转化为电荷
that become the image captured on the screen.
成为屏幕上捕获的图像。
Light particles or photons
光粒子或光子
leave the source, bounce
离开源头，反弹
off the subject and
偏离主题和
enter the camera through a series of
通过一系列进入相机
lenses.
镜头。
The photons then follow a designated
然后光子遵循指定的
path on their way from photon
从光子出发的路径
to photo.
去拍照。
A series of lenses allows the
一系列镜头允许
photographer to capture the clearest image
摄影师捕捉最清晰的图像
possible.
可能的。
This lens diaphragm is what
这个镜头光圈是什么
controls the amount of light that the photographer
控制摄影师的光量
allows in through the camera's opening
允许通过相机的开口进入
or aperture.
或光圈。
After crossing
穿越后
the diaphragm, the lenses
光圈、镜头
and entering the aperture,
并进入光圈，
the light bounces off a mirror and
光线从镜子反射回来
heads for the viewfinder.
头转向取景器。
Before it gets there, the light is flipped
在到达那里之前，灯会翻转
over as it passes through a prism.
当它穿过棱镜时。
That's so the image seen in the viewfinder is
所以在取景器中看到的图像是
right side up.
右侧朝上。
If the photographer likes the
如果摄影师喜欢
image, time to press the shutter
图像，按下快门的时间
button.
按钮。
The mirror lifts and the light rushes in.
镜子升起，光线涌入。
For a fraction of a second,
在不到一秒的时间里，
the light is not heading in the direction
光线没有照着这个方向
of the viewfinder.
取景器的。
But for the very heart of the digital camera,
但对于数码相机的核心来说，
the image sensor.
图像传感器。
The duration of this fraction
该部分的持续时间
of a second depends on the shutter
一秒取决于快门
that opens just long enough to
打开足够长的时间
expose the sensor to light.
将传感器暴露在光线下。
Now, to the real heart of this
现在，进入真正的核心
digital revolution, the element
数字革命，元素
that captures the image,
捕捉图像，
the image sensor. A tightly
图像传感器。紧紧地
structured grid made up of
结构化网格由
extremely tiny light sensors.
极其微小的光传感器。
When the photons hit the light sensor,
当光子撞击光传感器时，
they are absorbed by the semiconductor
它们被半导体吸收
material it's made of.
它的材质。
For each photon absorbed,
对于每个吸收的光子，
the light sensor emits an electric particle
光传感器发射出带电粒子
called an electron.
称为电子。
The photon's
光子的
energy transfers to the electron.
能量转移到电子。
That's the electrical charge.
这就是电荷。
The brighter the image,
图像越亮，
the stronger the electrical charge is.
电荷越强。
So each electrical charge
所以每个电荷
has a different intensity. A circuit
具有不同的强度。一个电路
board then converts the different intensities
然后板转换不同的强度
into computer language.
转化为计算机语言。
They represent millions of tiny colored
它们代表了数以百万计的小有色人种
dots that make up a photo.
构成照片的点。
The pixels.
像素。
The more pixels
像素越多
in a picture, the better the
在图片中，越好
resolution.
解决。
Okay.
好的。
So this is a new system.
所以这是一个新系统。
I'm not too sure why the
我不太确定为什么
echo is so strong.
回声是如此强烈。
Yeah. Okay. So we'll try to work with it.
是的。好的。所以我们会尝试使用它。
Okay.
好的。
So let's see.
那么让我们看看。
So this is a new system.
所以这是一个新系统。
So let's see.
那么让我们看看。
Okay.
好的。
So let's see.
那么让我们看看。
Okay. So we'll try to work with it
好的。所以我们会尝试使用它
for the time being.
暂且。
So this particular video just shows you
所以这个特定的视频只是向您展示
how we can actually,
我们实际上如何能够
the lights from the imaging source
来自成像源的光
can be converted into a particular
可以转换成特定的
image or video.
图像或视频。
It's because you have a sensor.
这是因为你有一个传感器。
And then for a particular sensor,
然后对于特定的传感器，
image sensor in the camera,
相机中的图像传感器，
actually it consists of many different
实际上它由许多不同的
elements. And these elements can actually
元素。而这些元素实际上可以
then convert the light or the photons
然后转换光或光子
into electric charges.
转化为电荷。
And these electric charges can then be converted
然后这些电荷可以转换
into some binary representation,
转化为某种二进制表示形式，
which is the pixels.
这是像素。
Okay. So this particular slide shows
好的。所以这张特别的幻灯片展示了
the signal flows of a digital camera.
数码相机的信号流。
So let's have a quick look at
让我们快速浏览一下
how the signal flow looks like.
信号流是什么样子的。
So first of all, you have some subjects.
首先，你有一些主题。
So the light will be collected by this
所以光线会被这个收集
lens here. So the lens will collect the light.
镜头在这里。所以镜头会收集光线。
Okay. And then it will hit this particular
好的。然后它会击中这个特定的
CCD. So this CCD is a
CCD。所以这个CCD是一个
types of image sensor.
图像传感器的类型。
So there are a few common types of
那么常见的有以下几种类型
image sensor. CCD
图像传感器。 CCD
is one of them. Right. CMOS
就是其中之一。正确的。互补金属氧化物半导体
is another one. Right. So this particular
是另一个。正确的。所以这个特殊的
CCD here, right,
CCD在这里，对吧，
from the video that you see just now, this CCD
从你刚才看到的视频来看，这个CCD
actually has a very packed
实际上有一个非常拥挤的
array or matrix
数组或矩阵
of sensor, which will then
传感器，然后将
convert the light into
将光转换成
some electric charges.
一些电费。
Okay. So afterwards you have
好的。所以之后你有
an analog to digital converter
模数转换器
to convert all these electric
将所有这些电力转换为
charges into the pixel value.
充入像素值。
Right. So for this pixel value,
正确的。所以对于这个像素值，
you can decide to, for example,
例如，您可以决定
store as a raw image.
存储为原始图像。
For those of you who play with
对于那些玩过的人
photography, sometimes you
摄影，有时你
may prefer to keep the image
可能更喜欢保留图像
in the raw format. Because
以原始格式。因为
if you keep it in the raw format, then you can
如果你保持原始格式，那么你可以
have access to the original data
可以访问原始数据
and you can do different types of
你可以做不同类型的
manipulation to
操纵
adjust the photo quality.
调整照片质量。
But for most people,
但对于大多数人来说，
we'll let the
我们会让
onboard processor in
板载处理器
the camera to do the processing.
相机进行处理。
So the processor, the image
所以处理器、图像
processing engine on the camera
相机上的处理引擎
will typically do the following.
通常会执行以下操作。
So first of all, you will do the
所以首先，您将执行以下操作
demossacking or the image reconstruction.
去马赛克或图像重建。
So you try to recover
所以你尝试恢复
three channels
三个通道
of color images.
彩色图像。
So this particular process is known as
所以这个特殊的过程被称为
reconstruction or demossacking.
重建或拆除。
And afterwards,
然后，
adjust the brightness, make sure that the
调整亮度，确保
image looks bright,
图像看起来明亮，
and then doing the white balancing.
然后进行白平衡。
So white balancing is that you make sure that
所以白平衡就是你要确保
white color, white
白色，白色
object will actually appear
物体实际上会出现
as if it's white color. Because
就好像它是白色的一样。因为
white color is very sensitive to
白色对颜色非常敏感
the light sources. When you capture an
光源。当您捕捉到一个
image, whether it will appear to be
图像，是否会出现
white or not depends on what kind of
白色与否取决于什么样的
light sources you are getting.
您获得的光源。
So this white balancing step will
所以这个白平衡步骤将
make sure that the white component
确保白色成分
will appear to be white.
会显得是白色的。
And afterwards, improve the sharpness,
然后，提高锐度，
you'll improve the contrast of the
你会提高对比度
image. So these are actually the
图像。所以这些实际上是
kind of processor,
一种处理器，
the onboard processing
机载处理
performed by the
由执行
camera. And afterwards,
相机。然后，
next you can then proceed to do the compression.
接下来您可以继续进行压缩。
Because typically the image, if you don't
因为通常图像，如果你不这样做
compress it, it's latched. So you need
压缩它，它被锁定。所以你需要
to perform the compression,
执行压缩，
but some common compression technique that you
但您可以使用一些常见的压缩技术
can use is, for example, the JPEG
例如，可以使用 JPEG
compression. Then you can compress it
压缩。然后就可以压缩了
and store it into your memory
并将其存储到你的记忆中
card. Or in some application,
卡片。或者在某些应用中，
for example, if you are trying to do
例如，如果你想这样做
some publishing application, then
一些发布应用程序，然后
the quality of the image is very important.
图像的质量非常重要。
Then you may store it uncompressed,
然后你可以不压缩地存储它，
for example using the TIFF format
例如使用 TIFF 格式
and store it into your memory card.
并将其存储到您的存储卡中。
So this is the typical signal flow.
这就是典型的信号流。
So when we want to talk
所以当我们想说话的时候
about a camera, what is the
关于相机，什么是
important criteria to determine
确定的重要标准
whether the quality of
质量是否
the camera, there's a few key factors.
相机，有几个关键因素。
So the first one is lens.
所以第一个是镜头。
This lens here.
这个镜头在这里。
So when you buy
所以当你购买时
a camera, for those of you who are into
一台相机，对于那些喜欢
photography, you'll know
摄影，你就会知道
that lens is very important and
这个镜头非常重要并且
it's very expensive.
它非常昂贵。
The role of the lens is that it's trying to
镜头的作用是它试图
collect the light from the
收集来自的光
imaging source. So therefore, whether a
成像源。因此，无论是
camera is good or not, the quality
相机好不好，质量
of the lens is a very important factor.
镜头的材质是一个非常重要的因素。
So the next one is CCD.
那么下一个就是CCD。
This particular part here, the sensor.
这里的这个特殊部分是传感器。
So this particular
所以这个特殊的
sensor, typically, if
传感器，通常，如果
the sensor has a higher resolution,
传感器具有更高的分辨率，
we consider it to be better.
我们认为这样更好。
For example, 10 megapixel
例如，10兆像素
sensor, usually we consider
传感器，通常我们考虑
it to be better than, for example, 3 megapixel
例如，它比 3 兆像素更好
sensor. But more
传感器。但更多的是
importantly is whether this sensor
重要的是这个传感器是否
is very sensitive to noise or not.
对噪音与否非常敏感。
When you take the photo, for example, in a
例如，当您在
very dark environment,
非常黑暗的环境，
whether the sensor is very sensitive to
传感器是否非常敏感
noise. So the quality of
噪音。所以质量
the sensor therefore is also an important factor.
因此传感器也是一个重要因素。
And then finally
然后最后
is this particular image processing engine
是这个特定的图像处理引擎吗
here. How well
这里。怎么样？
the
这
camera performs all these tasks here.
相机在这里执行所有这些任务。
So depending on different companies, for example,
所以根据不同的公司，例如，
whether you are
无论你是
Canon or whether you are Nikson,
无论你是佳能还是尼克森，
so different companies
所以不同的公司
have their own algorithm
有自己的算法
to perform these tasks here. So
在这里执行这些任务。所以
they are a little bit different. So that the
他们有点不同。从而使
performance of this particular image
这个特定图像的表现
processing engine will also determine
处理引擎还将确定
the quality of your camera and
你的相机的质量和
the captured images of video.
捕获的视频图像。
So therefore the digital image quality is
因此数字图像质量为
actually determined by these
实际上是由这些决定的
three factors here, which is shown.
这里显示了三个因素。
So it depends on the lens performance,
所以这取决于镜头性能，
CCD, image sensor,
CCD、图像传感器、
pixel count and performance, as
像素数和性能，如
well as the image processing
以及图像处理
engine performance. So these are
发动机性能。所以这些是
the factors that will determine
决定因素
the quality of the image.
图像的质量。
Right, so what are the
对了，那么有哪些
some common cameras?
一些常见的相机？
So this particular slide
所以这张特别的幻灯片
shows some of the common
显示了一些常见的
cameras that are available out there.
那里有可用的相机。
So the one that we have seen just now is
所以我们刚才看到的就是
the normal RGB kind of
正常的 RGB 类型
cameras. But in addition to that,
相机。但除此之外，
there are many other different cameras that are
还有许多其他不同的相机
out there. For example, one of the
在那里。例如，其中之一
other common cameras
其他常见相机
that we have is the RGBD.
我们拥有的是 RGBD。
So RGBD camera,
所以RGBD相机，
for example this Kinect camera.
例如这个 Kinect 相机。
So in addition to the RGB
所以除了RGB
information, it can also capture
信息，它还可以捕获
the depth information.
深度信息。
It can also capture the depth information.
它还可以捕获深度信息。
Another common
另一种常见的
types of camera that we have is
我们拥有的相机类型是
the near-infrared.
近红外线。
This type of cameras here.
这里有这种类型的相机。
Another common one is
另一种常见的就是
the thermal camera. For example,
热像仪。例如，
when you, during the
当你在期间
many years ago,
许多年前，
during the SARS period, I'm not sure
SARS期间，我不确定
whether you heard about SARS.
你是否听说过SARS。
Do you know about SARS?
你了解非典吗？
Okay, SARS, I think
好吧，我认为是SARS
occurred around
发生在周围
2003, around that time.
2003年，大约在那个时候。
And afterwards, the most recent one
然后是最近的一张
of us is COVID. So for those
我们中的一些人是新冠病毒。所以对于那些
you can use, for example, this kind of
例如，你可以使用这种
thermal camera to detect
热像仪检测
the body temperature. So it's
体温。所以这是
types of camera as well.
相机的类型也是如此。
And then another types of camera that we
然后我们使用另一种类型的相机
have is event-based camera.
有一个基于事件的相机。
So event-based camera
所以基于事件的相机
means that only when there's a change
意味着只有当发生变化时
of the brightness,
的亮度，
okay, of
好的，的
the imaging scene,
成像场景，
then it will be able, it will capture
那么它将能够，它将捕获
the information. So most of the time
的信息。所以大多数时候
it will not capture the information.
它不会捕获信息。
But when there's change of brightness, then it will
但是当亮度发生变化时，就会
capture. So the reason why
捕获。所以原因是
event-based camera is used in some
基于事件的相机被用于一些
applications is because it's
应用程序是因为它是
very power
非常有力量
efficient. Yeah, it can save
高效的。是的，可以节省
lots of energy. So therefore you can see
大量的能量。所以你可以看到
there's many different types of camera
有许多不同类型的相机
that can be used in different kind
可以用于不同种类
of application.
的应用程序。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay, so
好吧，那么
we have very briefly explained
我们已经非常简要地解释了
about image already. So next,
关于图像已经。那么接下来，
let's move on to video. So what's
让我们继续观看视频。那么什么是
video? Video is nothing but a sequence
视频？视频只不过是一个序列
of frame or images
帧或图像的
or pictures with audio
或带声音的图片
signal. So essentially all of us
信号。所以基本上我们所有人
should know that video is nothing but a
要知道视频只不过是
sequence of frame.
帧的序列。
Okay, and when you play this sequence
好的，当你播放这个序列时
of frame very quickly, and
帧的速度非常快，并且
due to the human persistence
由于人类的坚持
of vision, then you start to get the
的愿景，然后你开始得到
impression of smooth movement.
流畅运动的印象。
So that's essentially what a video
这就是视频的本质
is. Okay, and it also
是。好吧，还有它
has the audio component.
有音频组件。
So the different frame that we have, sometimes
所以有时我们有不同的框架
we call it frame, sometimes we call it
我们称之为框架，有时我们称之为
images, sometimes we call it pictures,
图像，有时我们称之为图片，
they refer to the same thing.
他们指的是同一件事。
Right, so as mentioned earlier on, we
是的，正如前面提到的，我们
play this video at a very high speed
以非常高的速度播放该视频
that gives the impression of the
给人的印象是
movement, a very smooth movement.
运动，非常流畅的运动。
Okay, due to the human persistence
好吧，由于人类的坚持
of vision. So this is the characteristics
的视觉。所以这就是特点
of the human vision system.
人类视觉系统。
So some popular video format
那么一些流行的视频格式
include MPAC, Moving Picture
包括 MPAC、动态图片
Expert Group,
专家组，
AVI, which is Intel, and then
AVI，也就是英特尔，然后
WMV, which is Microsoft.
WMV，即微软。
So this is some of the
所以这是一些
common video format.
常见的视频格式。
So next I will play you
那么接下来我就来玩你
a short video so I couldn't resist
一个短视频让我无法抗拒
because we are talking about video. So I
因为我们正在谈论视频。所以我
will just play you a video of one of my
只会给你播放我的一个视频
popular songs.
流行歌曲。
So
所以
yeah, so bear with me.
是的，所以请耐心听我说。
So this particular song is actually
所以这首歌实际上是
an example of a video.
视频示例。
So
所以
Ah, someday, someone will take this road
啊，总有一天，有人会走这条路
I will go, with my face turned to blue
我会走，脸色发青
I will go, farewell, I will be closed
我要走了，再见，我要关门了
So these are known as 480i
所以这些被称为 480i
And this particular i refers to interlace scanning
这个特定的 i 指的是隔行扫描
That we will explain a bit later here
我们稍后会在这里解释
And then for the PEL, for example, it says that it's 576i
然后对于 PEL，例如，它说它是 576i
That means the number of rows is 720
这意味着行数是 720
The width is 720 and the height of the number of rows is 576 here
这里的宽度是720，行数的高度是576
So therefore this number actually indicates the resolution
因此这个数字实际上表示分辨率
So the standard resolution is used in very early years
所以很早的时候就使用标准分辨率
That's why you can see the resolution actually is very small
这就是为什么你可以看到分辨率实际上非常小
And then afterwards we moved on to the high definition
然后我们转向高清
High definition is called HD
高清晰度称为HD
So under HD there's a few different variations
所以在高清下有一些不同的变化
The first one is 720p
第一个是720p的
So 720p refers to, this number here usually refers to the number of rows
所以720p指的是，这里的这个数字通常指的是行数
So 720p means 1280 by 720
所以 720p 意味着 1280 x 720
And this p here refers to progressive
而这里的p指的是渐进式
Later on we'll see what's the difference between interlace and progressive
稍后我们将了解隔行扫描和逐行扫描之间的区别
So the next one is 1080i
所以下一个是1080i
So 1080i refers to 1920 by 1080
所以1080i指的是1920乘1080
And then i refers to interlace
然后我指的是交错
And then finally 1080p is this resolution
最后1080p就是这个分辨率
And p is progressive
并且 p 是渐进的
So when you have this 1080p it also has a very unique name known as a full HD
因此，当您拥有 1080p 时，它还有一个非常独特的名称，即全高清
So maybe 10, 15 years ago when your parents go out and buy a TV from an electronic shop
所以也许 10、15 年前，当你的父母出去从电子商店购买电视时
And on the shop you see this full HD
在商店里你可以看到这个全高清
Actually it refers to this particular resolution with this scanning
实际上它指的是这种扫描的特定分辨率
And of course in recent years nowadays the TV that we have is the ultra high definition or UHD here
当然，近年来我们拥有的电视是超高清或UHD
So we typically see things like 4K or 8K
所以我们通常会看到 4K 或 8K 之类的东西
So 4K resolution is about four times the size of a full HD
因此 4K 分辨率大约是全高清尺寸的四倍
And the 8K resolution is four times the resolution of 4K
并且8K分辨率是4K分辨率的四倍
So all this number if you look at it, you may not have a good intuition of how it looks like
因此，如果您查看所有这些数字，您可能对它的样子没有很好的直觉
So if you look at this particular image it gives you an impression
所以如果你看这张特定的图片，它会给你一个印象
About how over time the number of pixels that you can squeeze into a single frame, how it has progressed
关于随着时间的推移，可以压缩到单个帧中的像素数量，它是如何进步的
So we start off with this SD and afterwards HD
所以我们从标清开始，然后是高清
4K, so most of our TV nowadays is using this 4K resolution
4K，所以现在我们大部分的电视都使用这个4K分辨率
And then 8K resolution is about this big
然后8K分辨率大约有这么大
So in the previous slide we introduced these terms about interlace scanning, I, and the progressive scanning, P
因此，在上一张幻灯片中，我们介绍了有关隔行扫描 I 和逐行扫描 P 的术语
So what's the difference between these two types of scan type?
那么这两种扫描类型有什么区别呢？
So interlace scanning refers to, given a particular, for example, image frame, if it's a video
因此，隔行扫描是指给定特定的图像帧（例如，如果它是视频）
So first of all we scan the odd line first and afterwards we scan the even line
所以首先我们先扫描奇数行，然后扫描偶数行
So sometimes we also call it top or bottom field
所以有时我们也称其为顶场或底场
So we scan the top field first, followed by the bottom field
所以我们首先扫描顶部字段，然后扫描底部字段
So if you do that, then this kind of scanning is known as interlace scanning
所以如果你这样做，那么这种扫描就称为隔行扫描
So it consists of two fields, odd or even line, or sometimes it's known as top and bottom field
因此它由两个场组成，奇数行或偶数行，或者有时称为顶场和底场
So it's scanned alternately
所以交替扫描
So this is an example of the interlace scanning
这是隔行扫描的一个例子
You can see it scans the odd line first, the blue line
你可以看到它首先扫描奇数行，蓝线
And afterwards it scans the red line here
然后它扫描这里的红线
So this is the interlace scanning
这就是隔行扫描
So as opposed to that, you have the next one which is the progressive scanning
与此相反，下一个是逐行扫描
So the progressive scanning is all the lines are scanned in sequence, so you scan it line by line
所以逐行扫描就是所有的行都是按顺序扫描的，所以你一行一行的扫描
So if you spare one moment to think about it, why do we want to do this interlace scan?
那么，如果您抽出一点时间思考一下，我们为什么要进行隔行扫描呢？
Why do we want to do interlace scanning? Especially in the early years
为什么我们要进行隔行扫描？尤其是早年
A lot of these standards were developed in the early years of video compression and transmission
其中许多标准是在视频压缩和传输的早期制定的
So for example, interlace scanning was developed during the time
例如，隔行扫描是在当时开发的
So why do you want to do interlace scanning?
那么为什么要进行隔行扫描呢？
Anyone?
有人吗？
So if you think about it, the reason why we want to do this interlace scanning
所以如果你想一想，我们为什么要进行隔行扫描
Is that each time when you're doing interlace scanning, we only scan half of the line
是不是每次你进行隔行扫描时，我们只扫描一半行
For example, we only scan the odd line for one frame, and afterwards we scan the even line
例如，我们只扫描奇数行一帧，然后扫描偶数行
So therefore what it means is that when you only scan the odd line and you transmit it
因此，这意味着当您只扫描奇数行并传输它时
The bandwidth that you use is only half
您使用的带宽只有一半
Because during the early days, bandwidth is very limited, it's very expensive
因为在早期，带宽非常有限，而且非常昂贵
So if you can reduce the number of bits that can be transmitted, you try to do that
因此，如果您可以减少可以传输的位数，您可以尝试这样做
So therefore people think of one way is that you only scan the top line first
因此人们想到一种方法就是先扫描顶行
And you transmit this particular frame
然后你传输这个特定的帧
So the bandwidth is reduced by half
所以带宽减少了一半
But there's also problems that you have
但也有你遇到的问题
So when you do that, as you can see, since you're only scanning half of the line
所以当你这样做时，正如你所看到的，因为你只扫描了一半的线
You're a little bit like cheating or cutting the corner
你有点像作弊或偷工减料
Because it's trying to trick our eye into trying to refresh
因为它试图欺骗我们的眼睛试图刷新
So even though there's some movement, it will trick your eye to interpret
所以即使有一些运动，它也会欺骗你的眼睛去解读
This frame has been refreshed already, there's a certain movement
这个帧已经刷新了，有一定的动静
So that is actually the trick
这实际上就是诀窍
The objective of interlace scanning is you reduce the number of lines
隔行扫描的目的是减少行数
And hence you reduce the bandwidth that you need to retransmit
因此，您可以减少重新传输所需的带宽
By trying to trick our brain into thinking that it's already updated some of the content
通过试图欺骗我们的大脑认为它已经更新了一些内容
But the problem of this kind of interlace scanning is that for some images
但这种隔行扫描的问题是，对于某些图像
Especially lines like this, when you have some imaging scene that has lots of edges and lines
尤其是像这样的线条，当您的成像场景有很多边缘和线条时
Some parts of the line are updated, other lines are not updated
部分线路更新，其他线路未更新
Then you are going to get this kind of jittering effect
然后你就会得到这种抖动的效果
So these are the jittering effects
这些就是抖动效果
So therefore, if you're using interlace scanning, the advantage is that you reduce the bandwidth
因此，如果您使用隔行扫描，优点是可以减少带宽
But the price you have to pay is that sometimes you'll get some content jittering
但你必须付出的代价是有时你会看到一些内容抖动
Like this, this is a very well-known example of jittering
像这样，这是一个非常著名的抖动例子
So as opposed to that, you can use this progressive scanning
因此，与此相反，您可以使用这种逐行扫描
You scan all the lines
你扫描所有的行
So the price you pay is that you transmit more bandwidth, but the quality is better
所以你付出的代价是传输更多的带宽，但质量更好
So that is during the early days
所以那是在早期
But nowadays because the bandwidth has actually increased a lot
但现在因为带宽实际上增加了很多
And the compression technique has improved a lot
而且压缩技术也进步了很多
So therefore nowadays we hardly use this interlace scanning anymore
所以现在我们几乎不再使用这种隔行扫描了
Most of them will be based on progressive scanning
其中大多数将基于逐行扫描
So earlier on we also mentioned about frame rate
所以前面我们也提到了帧率
So frame rate is referred to how many frames is played per second
所以帧率是指每秒播放多少帧
So it's given in terms of frames per second here
所以这里以每秒帧数给出
So depending on different countries and different standards
所以取决于不同的国家和不同的标准
For example, in Singapore and Australia, we use the PALS system
例如，在新加坡和澳大利亚，我们使用PALS系统
Which is the video is played at 25 frames per second
视频以每秒 25 帧的速度播放
And in the US and Japan, they use the NTSC standard
在美国和日本，他们使用 NTSC 标准
So the video is played at 30 frames per second
所以视频以每秒30帧的速度播放
So next we are going to very quickly look at some video signal processing and application
接下来我们将快速了解一些视频信号处理和应用
So what is video signal processing?
那么什么是视频信号处理呢？
So this is a very broad term as I mentioned
所以正如我提到的，这是一个非常广泛的术语
So video signal processing can deal with different aspects of video
所以视频信号处理可以处理视频的不同方面
So it can include things like representation
所以它可以包括诸如代表性之类的东西
So how do you present the video?
那么如何呈现视频呢？
Compression, how do you compress it into a small file size or low bit rate?
压缩，如何将其压缩成小文件或低比特率？
And afterwards, how do you store it?
然后，你如何存储它？
How do you transmit it?
你如何传输它？
How do you process it?
你如何处理它？
Analyze the content and understand what the content is
分析内容并了解内容是什么
So there's actually many different aspects of video
所以视频实际上有很多不同的方面
But for this particular course, we'll be focusing on these two topics
但对于这个特定的课程，我们将重点关注这两个主题
That I mentioned a few times already
我已经提到过几次了
So we'll be focusing on compression
所以我们将重点关注压缩
And then we'll be focusing on analytics and understanding
然后我们将专注于分析和理解
So next let's look at some of the sample signal processing applications
接下来让我们看看一些示例信号处理应用程序
So there are many, many different applications nowadays that are centered on video
所以现在有很多很多不同的以视频为中心的应用程序
So for example, we can have a business streaming e-commerce
例如，我们可以拥有一个流媒体电子商务业务
This is particularly popular in China
这在中国特别受欢迎
Almost every year
几乎每年
Very, very popular in China
在中国非常非常受欢迎
And then entertainment, for example, video streaming, video on demand
然后是娱乐，例如视频流、视频点播
Some typical examples would be Netflix
一些典型的例子是 Netflix
Any movie that you want to watch, you can just stream it
任何你想看的电影，都可以直接观看
Technology, technology enabled learning online lecture
技术，技术使学习在线讲座
So a few years back during COVID, it was quite serious
几年前的新冠疫情期间，情况相当严重
So we have to actually conduct most of our lectures online
所以我们实际上必须在网上进行大部分讲座
So other things like, for example, in smart cities transportation
所以其他事情，例如在智慧城市交通中
The autonomous vehicles that you have
您拥有的自动驾驶汽车
The video analytics
视频分析
So for example, the autonomous vehicles
例如，自动驾驶汽车
I just read, I think a few weeks ago or last month in Wuhan
我刚刚读到，我想是几周前或上个月在武汉
There's actually a new service, right?
实际上有一项新服务，对吗？
It's a Luo Bo Kuai Pao
这是萝卜快炮
So for those applications, you need to be able to see the surroundings
因此对于这些应用程序，您需要能够看到周围的环境
And be able to perform tasks like segmentation, detection and so on
并能够执行分割、检测等任务
Okay, so next I'm just going to
好的，接下来我要
I think for Chinese students definitely you know what this
我想对于中国学生来说你肯定知道这是什么
直播代货
So I'm just going to, I'm not going to do that here
所以我只是要，我不会在这里这样做
Even though I'm tempted to show my QR code
尽管我很想出示我的二维码
And then you can also use some
然后你还可以使用一些
火箭,大炮 or whatever
火箭、大炮或者其他什么
But okay, I'm not doing here
但好吧，我不在这里做
I'm just trying to show you some of the possible applications of video processing
我只是想向您展示视频处理的一些可能的应用
So this is live streaming in China
这就是中国的直播
Okay, so I'll just play a short segment of it
好的，那我就播放一小段
Because the video is a bit long, so I'll just play a short segment
由于视频有点长，所以只播放一小段
直播代货
Sorry, because I don't pay for the Google subscription
抱歉，因为我不支付 Google 订阅费用
So they always show me the advertisement
所以他们总是给我看广告
This is live stream shopping
这是直播购物
One of the hottest trends in China
中国最热门的趋势之一
Every night, tens of millions of people watch live shows
每晚都有千万人观看直播
Hosted by influencers like VIA and by the products they recommend
由 VIA 等有影响力的人士及其推荐的产品主办
Or on e-commerce and social apps like Taobao and Douyin
或者在淘宝和抖音等电子商务和社交应用上
The sister app of TikTok
TikTok的姊妹应用
It's not about only shopping
这不仅仅是购物
It's about the experience, it's about having fun
重要的是体验，重要的是享受
You got to see 3D, you got to see in some kind of action
你必须看到 3D，你必须看到某种动作
It's almost like a theatre act
这几乎就像一场戏剧表演
The internet craze has taken over China
互联网热潮席卷中国
By the end of 2020, the country had almost 400 million live stream shopping users
截至2020年底，全国直播购物用户规模近4亿
China's live stream e-commerce market has also grown dramatically
中国直播电商市场也大幅增长
With an estimated value of 161 billion dollars in 2020
2020年预计价值1610亿美元
It's becoming popular outside China as well
在中国以外也开始流行
So is live streaming the future of shopping?
那么直播是购物的未来吗？
Live streaming is not a new thing
直播并不是什么新鲜事
In China, it started in 2015 with the rollout of 4G
在中国，从 2015 年 4G 的推出开始
And it was first used for entertainment and socializing
它最初是用于娱乐和社交
Many live streamers perform for their followers or chat it to them
许多直播主播为他们的粉丝表演或与他们聊天
Making money by receiving virtual currency and gifts
通过接收虚拟货币和礼物来赚钱
In the West, live streaming is mainly the doming of avid gamers
在西方，直播主要是狂热游戏玩家的统治
In China, it's broken into e-commerce
在中国，它进军电子商务
China actually has a very big e-commerce empire
中国实际上有一个非常大的电子商务帝国
So it uses these super apps, what we call
所以它使用了这些超级应用程序，我们称之为
That you have payment, you have search of information
你有付款，你有信息搜索
You have recommendation system
你有推荐系统
And you have huge amount of goods available on the platform
并且平台上有大量商品可供选择
And as well as a lot of consumers
还有很多消费者
So with this advantage, they merge these features of live streaming
所以利用这个优势，他们融合了直播的这些特点
To make the influencers actually sell goods
让网红真正卖货
Here is a perfect choice
这里是一个完美的选择
Nice neutrals, beautiful prints, nothing overwhelming
漂亮的中性色，漂亮的印花，没有什么压倒性的
And the warmth and comfort of flannel
还有法兰绒的温暖和舒适
Traditional TV shopping involves a one-way direction
传统电视购物涉及单向方向
Whereby a host introduces a product, demonstrates certain things
主持人介绍产品、展示某些事物
And say call this number or something
并说拨打这个号码或其他什么
But live stream shopping is live
但直播购物是直播
That in itself is a very, very big difference
这本身就是一个非常非常大的区别
That causes different psychology
从而导致不同的心理
And live stream shopping is a very entertaining way of engaging someone else
直播购物是一种非常有趣的吸引他人的方式
When you shop, actually this live streaming video will continue
当你购物的时候，其实这个直播视频还会继续
It will minimize into a corner
它将最小化到一个角落
And you can buy the items and pay all on the same app
您可以在同一个应用程序上购买商品并付款
After that, the live streaming screen will just enlarge by itself
之后直播画面就会自行放大
And the promoter will come back to screen
发起人将回到屏幕
So it's like very convenient
所以感觉很方便
Taobao, one of China's biggest e-commerce platforms
淘宝，中国最大的电子商务平台之一
Owned by tech giant Alibaba
归科技巨头阿里巴巴所有
Added a live streaming function in early 2016
2016年初新增直播功能
In the following years, other e-commerce and social platforms
在接下来的几年里，其他电子商务和社交平台
Like JD and Douyin also integrated this feature
像京东和抖音也集成了这个功能
But in the past few years, it's been difficult to make a breakthrough
但这几年却很难有所突破
People were in lockdown and many retailers were pushed online
人们处于封锁状态，许多零售商被迫转向线上
OK, so it's a long video. So I'm not going to...
好吧，所以这是一个很长的视频。所以我不会...
long video so I'm not going to yeah I'm not going to play the whole video but you can see now yeah
视频很长，所以我不会播放整个视频，但你现在可以看到是的
in the past this Alibaba Jingdong is very big but I heard nowadays actually people don't buy so much
以前这个阿里巴巴京东很大但是我听说现在人其实不买那么多了
from it anymore usually what people nowadays is using Pingdol right that's that's why I heard
现在人们通常都在使用 Pingdol，这就是我听说的原因
from my wife yeah so nowadays people tend to buy very cheap stuff from Pingdol but recently I
来自我妻子 是的，所以现在人们倾向于从 Pingdol 购买非常便宜的东西，但最近我
think last year or a few months ago there's also this event ZhaDian right you are you aware of it
想想去年或者几个月前也有这个事件炸店吧你知道吗
okay if you do not know you can go and find out later anyway yeah so okay so this is actually
好吧，如果你不知道，你可以稍后去了解一下，是的，好吧，这实际上是
therefore like video streaming right so one of the very important criteria is in order to support
因此，就像视频流一样，非常重要的标准之一是为了支持
applications such as video streaming you must have a very powerful video compression and
像视频流这样的应用程序你必须有非常强大的视频压缩和
streaming technology to support it so that's what we are going to study later on for this course
流技术来支持它，这就是我们稍后将在本课程中研究的内容
which is how do we perform very efficient video compression and streaming and transmission
这就是我们如何执行非常高效的视频压缩、流媒体和传输
okay
好的
okay another application just as video on demand so video on demand okay so this again is one of
好吧，另一个应用程序就像视频点播所以视频点播好吧，这又是其中之一
my very favorite animation right so I'll also would like to share with you so that you can
我非常喜欢的动画，所以我也想与您分享，以便您可以
relax a bit more
放松一点
from master filmmaker Hayao Miyazaki the director of the academy award-winning
来自电影大师宫崎骏、学院奖导演
spirited away that is ancient sorcery quite powerful too
千与千寻那是古老的魔法也相当强大
this summer experience the epic tale of a young woman transformed by a mysterious curse
今年夏天，体验一位被神秘诅咒改变的年轻女子的史诗故事
oh that's really me isn't it an enchanted moving castle this is a magic house
哦，这真的是我，这不是一座神奇的移动城堡，这是一座神奇的房子
and the one wizard powerful enough to set her free this charm will guarantee your safe return
一位强大到足以让她自由的巫师，这个咒语将保证你安全返回
Walt Disney Studios presents a studio jiggly production of a Hayao Miyazaki film
华特迪士尼工作室推出宫崎骏电影的工作室制作
hold on
坚持，稍等
this June journey to amazing new worlds
这个六月的奇妙新世界之旅
aboard Howl's moving castle
登上哈尔的移动城堡
okay so this animation is also my daughter's favorite
好吧，这个动画也是我女儿的最爱
okay so the next short video that I'm going to show is about video analytics so right nowadays
好的，我要展示的下一个短视频是关于视频分析的，所以现在就是这样
you know that when together with AI and video you can do many tasks right so this particular
你知道，当与人工智能和视频结合使用时，你可以正确完成许多任务，所以这个特殊的任务
video is mainly going to be focusing from the surveillance and analytics perspective
视频主要从监控和分析的角度关注
so just to demonstrate some of the potential use cases
所以只是为了展示一些潜在的用例
so
所以
okay so just now from the particular video you can see that there's actually many kind of
好的，刚才从特定视频中您可以看到实际上有很多种
tasks that can be achieved it turned out that actually currently I do have a project with an
可以实现的任务 事实证明，实际上目前我确实有一个项目
industrial partner a lots of the tasks that's being described in the video actually we are also
工业合作伙伴 视频中描述的许多任务实际上我们也在
doing it so we are quite familiar with some of those topics so pretty much for the particular
这样做是为了让我们对其中一些主题非常熟悉，因此对于特定的主题非常熟悉
industrial project for example from the safety perspective we need to be able to detect smoke
例如，从安全角度来看，工业项目我们需要能够检测烟雾
fire know whether persons are wearing the know the mask especially during the covid
消防人员知道人们是否戴口罩，尤其是在新冠疫情期间
period whether they are wearing the protective here PPE personal protective equipment okay
期间他们是否穿戴防护服 PPE 个人防护装备 还好
also things like we try to you know track the movements of different objects
还有像我们试图让你知道的事情跟踪不同物体的运动
know count the person know perform action recognition human object interaction and so on
知道计数人知道执行动作识别人类物体交互等等
so these are some of the things that we can do to analyze the video application
所以这些是我们可以做的一些事情来分析视频应用程序
okay let me see all right let me probably just quickly cover the next
好吧，让我看看，好吧，让我快速介绍下一个
uh two slides and then we'll you know take a short break so what are the current trends in
嗯，两张幻灯片，然后我们会让您休息一下，那么当前的趋势是什么
no video signal processing so right of course in recent years we see that there's new
没有视频信号处理所以当然近年来我们看到有新的
ai and deep learning algorithm and models right okay so this is particularly used in the context
人工智能和深度学习算法和模型是正确的，所以这是特别在上下文中使用的
of video analytics and understanding okay and also progressively we have more and more
视频分析和理解还不错，而且我们也逐渐拥有越来越多的
data that's being collected so therefore a new train will be the big data okay from the
正在收集的数据，因此新火车将是来自
processing perspective we have a better processor larger storage devices and also there's a new
从处理的角度来看，我们有更好的处理器更大的存储设备，而且还有一个新的
emerging consumer behavior that supports some of the application for example the video that
支持某些应用程序的新兴消费者行为，例如视频
just now we show about the you know the e-commerce live streaming e-commerce these are some of the
刚才我们展示了你知道的电子商务直播电子商务这些是一些
emerging or new consumer behaviors that require the underlying technology to support it okay and
新兴或新的消费者行为需要底层技术的支持
of course over the years we have a better and better compression algorithm so this is what
当然，多年来我们有越来越好的压缩算法，所以这就是
we are going to study as our next topic and then we have a better video analytics uh techniques
我们将作为下一个主题进行研究，然后我们就有更好的视频分析呃技术
so in terms of the technical challenges so for this particular course as i mentioned we are
因此，就技术挑战而言，对于我提到的这个特定课程，我们
be focusing on two things number one is the compression or coding yeah number two is on
专注于两件事，第一件事是压缩或编码，第二件事是
the content analysis and understanding so from the perspective of compression and coding some of the
所以从压缩和编码的角度对内容进行分析和理解一些
challenges is that we want our video always to have a better quality lower bit rate okay and also you
挑战是我们希望我们的视频始终具有更好的质量和更低的比特率，好吧，还有你
need to uh offer a certain quality of services for example just now in the live streaming we need to
需要呃提供一定质量的服务，例如现在在直播中我们需要
make sure that you know the delay the latency the video is smooth and so on right so from the context
确保您从上下文中了解延迟、延迟、视频是否流畅等
of uh no video content analysis and understanding so some of the challenges that we have is that
呃，没有视频内容分析和理解，所以我们面临的一些挑战是
robust performance for example just now in the video that you see you do counting right you try
强大的性能，例如刚才在视频中，您看到您尝试计数正确
to detect uh no ppe right you try to detect for example uh post estimation you try to estimate
要检测呃没有个人防护装备，你尝试检测例如呃后估计你尝试估计
you try to analyze the whether when the worker is performing certain tasks whether it's uh no help
您尝试分析工人何时执行某些任务是否没有帮助
no kind of harmful to their uh posture and so on those we need to have a robust performance
不会对他们的呃姿势等有害，我们需要有强劲的表现
so therefore robust performance is one of the key challenge so another common challenge that we have
因此，稳健的性能是关键挑战之一，因此我们面临的另一个共同挑战
is the domain gap or shift or generalization so for example if you train on this data set right
是域差距、移位或泛化，例如，如果您在此数据集上进行训练
you train on this data set but later on when you want to deploy to a new environment
您在此数据集上进行训练，但稍后当您想要部署到新环境时
are you able to still achieve good performance right so this is the domain gap or shift or
你是否仍然能够获得良好的性能，所以这是领域差距或转变或
generalization problem okay so other issues uh very well known in ai uh domain is no annotation
泛化问题还好，所以其他问题在 ai 领域众所周知，没有注释
data collections and annotations are always expensive right so how do we address those
数据收集和注释总是很昂贵，那么我们如何解决这些问题
problems that's why you have things like no nowadays uh pre-trained model followed by
问题这就是为什么你现在没有预训练模型之类的原因
fine tuning or adaptation is becoming very uh popular it's because the data annotation is very
微调或适应变得非常流行，因为数据注释非常
expensive but there's also other techniques like no training with a small number of data such as
昂贵，但还有其他技术，例如无需使用少量数据进行训练，例如
few short learning and even training without no training data right which is for example known
很少有短期学习，甚至在没有已知训练数据的情况下进行训练
as a zero short learning so these are some active research direction and challenge in this space here
作为零短期学习，所以这些是这个领域的一些活跃的研究方向和挑战
right okay so with that i think we'll take a short break let's come back at say uh 8 15
好的，所以我想我们会休息一下，然后在 8 月 15 日回来
let's come back 8 15
我们回来吧 8 15
you
你
okay so let's continue so just now during the break there are some students asking some questions
好的，我们继续吧，刚才休息的时候有一些学生问一些问题
regarding the exam so just now i just probably want to add on her which is uh this particular
关于考试，所以现在我可能想补充一下她，呃，这个特别的
course right so in the past actually there are two lecturers who are teaching so uh last for example okay
当然是对的，所以过去实际上有两位讲师在教学，所以呃最后一个例子，好吧
this course is offered in both semester semester one as well as semester two so the previous semester
这门课程在第一学期和第二学期都提供，所以上一学期
there's actually a guest lecturer okay and then uh the semester before actually there's a second
实际上有一位客座讲师，好吧，然后呃，之前的学期实际上有第二位
lecture so therefore uh that means what what i'm trying to say is that no uh usually i would suggest
讲座所以呃这意味着我想说的是不呃通常我会建议
students can actually if they are not too sure about the exam question they can go to the uh library
事实上，如果学生对考试题不太确定，他们可以去呃图书馆
and then download past year exam question for you know a few years like two years or so then roughly
然后下载去年的考试题，你知道几年，比如两年左右，然后大致
you have a certain feel about what kind of questions you will come out already but it's just that for
你已经对自己会提出什么样的问题有一定的感觉，但这只是为了
this particular course because for the past semesters there's always a second lecture so therefore uh
这门特殊的课程因为过去的学期总是有第二堂课所以所以呃
what i'm trying to say is that i would still encourage you to know go to the library download
我想说的是，我仍然鼓励您知道去图书馆下载
the past year exam question but only look at for example the first two questions yeah because the
去年的考试问题，但只看前两个问题，是的，因为
first two questions are uh set by me the last two questions depending on which year sometimes is set
前两个问题是我设置的，最后两个问题有时取决于哪一年设置
by another lecture so therefore with that then you have a better appreciation or feeling about how
通过另一场讲座，因此您可以更好地欣赏或感受如何
the question will look like so that's one suggestion the second suggestion the second point is actually
问题看起来像这样，这是一个建议，第二个建议，第二点实际上是
for a lot of the uh past year exam question for my lecture notes i'll try to include them into the
对于我的讲义中去年的很多考试问题，我会尝试将它们包含在
lecture notes and then we'll go through those uh exercises and questions together so in even if
讲义，然后我们将一起完成那些呃练习和问题，所以即使
you do not go and download those uh exam past year exam question but you by going through the lecture
你不会去下载那些呃考试去年的考试问题，而是通过听讲座
exercises you would still have a certain feeling or familiarity with what kind of question they'll
您仍然会对他们会提出什么样的问题有一定的感觉或熟悉
be asked okay so therefore you don't have to worry too much so it's up to you if you want to
可以被问到，所以你不必太担心，所以这取决于你是否愿意
download the question from the library okay just be a bit aware that some of the question is set by
从图书馆下载问题，好吧，请注意，有些问题是由
the second lecture so it may not be relevant okay so yeah and second is that you can also refer to
第二个讲座所以它可能不相关，好吧所以是的，第二个是你也可以参考
our you know lecture exercise you know as far as possible i'll usually at least include some past
我们的“你知道”讲座练习你尽可能知道，我通常至少会包括一些过去的内容
year exam question in the exercise okay in the lectures so that's the first point i just want to
练习中的年度考试问题在讲座中可以，所以这是我想要的第一点
clarify uh the second point actually early on i already mentioned early on so uh for this year
澄清呃第二点实际上很早就我已经提到过所以呃今年
in terms of the dissertation right um yeah because we received really many many applications
就论文而言，嗯是的，因为我们收到了很多申请
so unfortunately we don't have time to be able to reply each individual email so that's why you know
很遗憾，我们没有时间回复每封电子邮件，因此您知道
we want to ask for know your understanding that we will not be able to reply every single email
我们无法回复每一封电子邮件，请您谅解
because there are just too many of them and also when we or at least for myself usually because
因为它们太多了，而且当我们或至少我自己通常因为
there are so many applications so usually when i look at a student if i feel that he's a good
有很多申请，所以通常当我看一个学生时，如果我觉得他是一个好人
student i'll assign the projects to him or her already and then afterwards i'll finish the
学生，我已经将项目分配给他或她，然后我将完成
assignment of all my projects but subsequently actually there are a lot other strong students
我所有项目的作业，但随后实际上还有很多其他优秀的学生
so therefore please don't feel that you know because i do not choose your you know choose you
所以请不要觉得你知道，因为我不选择你，你知道选择你
is because you are not a good student it's just that there are too many and some of they are
是因为你不是好学生，只是数量太多，有些是
actually some very strong students but somehow at the end i only uh kind of notice them later
实际上有一些非常优秀的学生，但不知怎的，最后我只是呃后来才注意到他们
okay sometimes it's a the area may not match so well but sometimes it's just the way you know we
好吧，有时这是一个区域可能不太匹配，但有时这只是你了解我们的方式
just assign the projects so yeah i just want to clarify that so at least some of you have a
只是分配项目所以是的我只是想澄清一下所以至少你们中的一些人有一个
certain understanding why i did not reply to some of your email okay
一定理解为什么我没有回复你的一些电子邮件好吗
so
所以
all right okay so the next thing we are going to talk about is a few image and video standards
好吧，接下来我们要讨论的是一些图像和视频标准
here right so this slides give a quick summary of some of the image and video standards right
这张幻灯片快速总结了一些图像和视频标准
so if you have a quick look there's a few different entities or organizations that develop
因此，如果您快速浏览一下，就会发现有一些不同的实体或组织正在开发
standards so in early years we have this organization known as itut so itut they develop
标准，所以早年我们有一个名为 itut 的组织，所以 itut 他们开发了
the standards they they develop is called h.26x series so you can see a 261 okay 262 263 264 so
他们开发的标准称为 h.26x 系列，因此您可以看到 261 好 262 263 264 所以
these are the standards that's developed by itut okay and then there's another organization which
这些是国际电信联盟制定的标准，好吧，还有另一个组织
is impact also known as iso so for iso the standard that they develop they call impact series so you
冲击也称为 ISO，所以对于 ISO，他们开发的标准称为冲击系列，所以您
have impact one impact two impact four all right and so on and so forth right they are also sometimes
有影响一 影响二 影响四 好吧，依此类推，对，有时也是
when this itut and iso they try to develop the standard together right so some of the well-known
当国际电信联盟和国际标准化组织尝试共同制定标准时，一些众所周知的标准
one is actually this impact two actually this impact two by right they should draw it here
一实际上是这个影响二实际上是这个影响二对了他们应该把它画在这里
because it's jointly developed by them okay h.264 is also jointly developed by them and then h.265
因为它是他们联合开发的好吧h.264也是他们联合开发的然后h.265
so some of the standards are jointly developed by them so on top of that you also have some other
所以有些标准是由他们联合制定的，所以除此之外你还有其他一些标准
organization for example this uh society of moving picture and television engineer they develop vc1
组织例如这个呃电影和电视工程师协会他们开发了vc1
standard and google they also develop their own sets of standards as well so these are a few
标准和谷歌他们也制定了自己的标准集，所以这些是一些
different organizations that develop the video standard so when they talk about video standard
开发视频标准的不同组织因此当他们谈论视频标准时
what it means is a video compression okay or coding standard so let's quickly go through some
它的意思是视频压缩或编码标准，所以让我们快速浏览一下
of these well-known standards so the first standard that we have is the jpeg standard so jpeg i think
在这些众所周知的标准中，我们拥有的第一个标准是 jpeg 标准，所以我认为 jpeg
most some of you probably have heard about it before it's a very popular image compression
你们中的大多数人可能在它成为一种非常流行的图像压缩之前就听说过它
standard so it's used to compress image so jpeg is also known as iso iec international standard
标准，因此用于压缩图像，因此 jpeg 也称为 iso iec 国际标准
10918 or itut recommendation t.81 so of course you don't have to memorize this number
10918 或 itut 建议 t.81 所以当然你不必记住这个号码
you know it's just kind of for your information right so officially jpeg is known as these two
你知道这只是为了给你提供信息，所以正式 jpeg 被称为这两个
standards so if any of you are interested you can go and download this particular
标准，所以如果你们中的任何人感兴趣，您可以去下载这个特定的
jpeg standard it's the size of a book right so there's no need to go and spend too much time
jpeg 标准，正好是一本书的大小，因此无需花费太多时间
reading it up okay and it's developed by a particular body known as joint photographic
仔细阅读它，它是由一个称为联合摄影的特定机构开发的
expert group or jpeg so that's why this particular image compression standard
专家组或 jpeg，这就是为什么这个特定的图像压缩标准
afterwards you know take over the name of this body that developed the standard
之后您就知道接管制定该标准的机构的名称
right okay so next we are going to look at the families of mpeg standards here so mpeg standard
好吧，接下来我们要看看 mpeg 标准的家族，所以 mpeg 标准
started in 92 right so the first standard that was developed is called mpeg one right so mpeg one
开始于 92 对，所以开发的第一个标准称为 mpeg one 对，所以 mpeg one
is a standard that contain video compression and it also perform audio compression right so at the
是一个包含视频压缩的标准，它还执行音频压缩，因此
time is trying to target the application which is like you know for cd-rom okay for cd-rom right so
时间正在尝试定位应用程序，就像您知道的 cd-rom 一样，对于 cd-rom 来说也可以，所以
i'm not even too sure for your generation whether you know what cd-rom right so cd-rom is something
我什至不太确定你们这一代人是否知道什么是 cd-rom，所以 cd-rom 是一种东西
like this that is like the music cd that you listen to right so but it's for computer so that's
就像这样，就像你听的音乐CD一样，但它是用于电脑的，所以这是
cd-rom so at the time is targeting for cd-rom and the bit rate is 1.5 megabits per second so that's
cd-rom，所以当时的目标是 cd-rom，比特率为每秒 1.5 兆比特，所以这是
the target bit rate so arising from this particular mpeg one standard there's a particular commercial
目标比特率，因此由这个特定的 mpeg 一个标准产生，有一个特定的商业广告
product arising from it which is known as the vcd so any one of you have watched vcd before
由此产生的产品被称为 vcd，所以你们中的任何一个人以前都看过 vcd
right it's probably two you are still too young so at the time i still remember i was in i can
是的，可能是两岁了，你还太年轻，所以当时我还记得我在我可以
remember in in high school or in university if you want to watch a standard movie 60 minute
如果你想看一部 60 分钟的标准电影，记得在高中或大学时
a movie you need two of this vcd this okay right so this is uh during the early years
一部电影你需要两张这样的 VCD 没关系，所以这是早年的呃
right okay and afterwards uh things of course start to progress then we move on to mpeg two
好吧，然后呃事情当然开始进展然后我们继续 mpeg 2
standard so mpeg two standard is also known as the h.262 right so it was developed in 94 many
标准所以mpeg二标准也被称为h.262对所以它是在94年制定的
years ago so one of the key characteristics of this mpeg two standard is that it's a video and
几年前，这个 mpeg 两个标准的关键特征之一是它是一个视频和
audio coding with different profile okay so this different profile means that is trying to target
具有不同配置文件的音频编码好吧，所以这个不同的配置文件意味着正在尝试定位
for different use cases in application right okay so in different applications sometimes there's a
对于应用程序中的不同用例，好吧，所以在不同的应用程序中有时会有一个
different uh you know kind of image quality requirement some of them can be smaller some
不同的呃你知道图像质量要求有些可以更小一些
of them the the size can be bigger and also their quality uh quality expectation is different okay
其中尺寸可以更大，而且质量呃质量期望也不同好吗
some is probably for lower end kind of use cases some is for some higher quality video so because
有些可能用于低端用例，有些用于更高质量的视频，所以因为
of that you have a wider range of the bit rate okay so for mpeg two it can cover a wider range
其中你有更广泛的比特率范围，所以对于 mpeg 2 它可以覆盖更广泛的范围
of bit rate from two to 80 megabits per second so the relevant products okay so the product arising
比特率从每秒 2 兆比特到 80 兆比特，因此相关产品还可以，因此产品出现了
from this mpeg two is a dvd i think dvd very likely you probably heard about it if not at
从这个 mpeg 两个是一张 DVD，我认为 DVD 很可能你可能听说过它，如果不是在
least your parents you know should still have some uh dvds from the older days okay and then
至少你知道你的父母应该还保留着一些以前的 DVD 好吧，然后
things start to uh move on then we have the mpeg four so mpeg four is actually a content based video
事情开始进展，然后我们有了 mpeg 4，所以 mpeg 4 实际上是一个基于内容的视频
coding that means you try to contain uh perform video compression by looking at the content of
编码意味着您尝试通过查看内容来包含呃执行视频压缩
the video right so some of the very unique features of mpeg four is that uh it provide
视频正确，所以 mpeg 4 的一些非常独特的功能是它提供
uh coding coding actually also means compression so coding or compressions of natural or synthetic
呃编码实际上也意味着压缩所以自然或合成的编码或压缩
media objects so either the object is natural occurring or whether it's for example some
媒体对象，因此该对象要么是自然发生的，要么是某些
animation the kind of generated content or synthetic content so mpeg four is used to target
动画 生成内容或合成内容的类型，因此使用 mpeg 4 来定位
to compress those kinds of uh content right okay then afterwards we move on to the h.26x series of
压缩这些类型的内容，好吧，然后我们继续讨论 h.26x 系列
the standards okay so this is another important family of the standards here so it started in
标准还可以，所以这是这里标准的另一个重要系列，所以它开始于
many years ago it started off with a h.261 so it's developed in uh 90s right by this particular
许多年前，它从 h.261 开始，所以它是在 90 年代由这个特定的人开发的
organization known as the ccitt so ccitt again the name you don't have to memorize it's just
组织称为 ccitt，所以 ccitt 再次是您不必记住的名称，它只是
for your information so ccitt stand for international telegraph and telephone consultative committee
供您参考，ccitt 代表国际电报和电话咨询委员会
right but this uh body later on was renamed as itut right if you look at the full name is international
是的，但是这个呃机构后来被更名为itut，如果你看一下全名是international，就对了
telecom nation union international telecom nations standardization sector right so you don't have to
电信国家联盟 国际电信国家标准化部门的权利，因此您不必
worry too much about it because it's quite a lot but probably what you need to know is that
太担心了，因为它太多了，但可能你需要知道的是
right this standard was uh developed by itut okay so uh this particular standard is uh based on dct
是的，这个标准是由 itut 开发的，所以这个特定标准是基于 DCT 的
based video compression uh scheme so dct is a discrete cosine transform so it's the types of
基于视频压缩呃方案，所以 DCT 是离散余弦变换，所以它的类型
uh transform that we are going to study later on so therefore for this particular standard h.261
嗯，我们稍后将研究这个变换，因此对于这个特定的标准 h.261
right is used to perform video compression and is using this particular dct transform
右边用于执行视频压缩并使用这种特定的 DCT 变换
discrete cosine transform okay and it has many similarity with mpeg-1 okay its original target
离散余弦变换好吧，它与 mpeg-1 有很多相似之处，好吧它的原始目标
application is for video conferencing so originally when uh no the body developed this h.261
应用程序用于视频会议，所以最初当呃不，机构开发了这个 h.261
is mainly for uh tele video or teleconferencing so that means no when i call you right you'll
主要用于呃电话视频或电话会议，所以这意味着不，当我打电话给你时，你会
be able to talk to me in uh real time so because it's used for video conferencing therefore their
能够实时与我交谈，因为它用于视频会议，所以他们
bit rate requirement is very low yeah because it's for video conferencing that means you need to be
比特率要求非常低，是的，因为它用于视频会议，这意味着您需要
able to perform the compression very quickly yeah so you need to be fast you need to compress it
能够非常快地执行压缩是的，所以你需要很快，你需要压缩它
very quickly and you need to transmit this particular video right very quickly that means
非常快，您需要非常快地传输该特定视频，这意味着
the bit rate need to be very low so therefore for this h.261 their bit rate is a multiple of
比特率需要非常低，因此对于 h.261，它们的比特率是
64 kilobits per second right so first 64 kilobits per second is very low okay so yeah whereas the p
64 kbps 是的，所以第一个 64 kbps 非常低，好吧，所以是的，而 p
can run from uh values of 1 to 30 so it's actually very low bit rate so therefore you can kind of
可以从 1 到 30 的值运行，所以它实际上是非常低的比特率，因此你可以
recognize in the early days right h.26 series of standard initially is mainly used for you know
早期认识对的h.26系列标准最初主要是用于大家知道的
video conferencing therefore the requirement is that it has to be low bit rate the compression
因此视频会议的要求是它必须是低比特率压缩
need to be fast yeah because you are using it for video conferencing okay and then afterwards uh no
需要快点是的，因为你正在使用它进行视频会议，好吧，然后呃不
the next major standard right there's actually a h.262 right okay if you see this one now there's
下一个主要标准实际上是 h.262 好吧，如果你现在看到这个
a h.263 already what happened to h.262
h.263 已经发生了 h.262 的情况
right you can see it's a h.261 usually 261 you expect 262 263 and so on right so what happened
是的，您可以看到它是 h.261，通常是 261，您期望的是 262 263 等等，所以发生了什么
there's a missing h.262
缺少 h.262
so it turned out that right if you remember this uh iso and itut sometimes they work together they
所以事实证明，如果你还记得这个呃 iso 和 itut 有时它们会一起工作，那就对了
collaborate so it turned out that this h.262 is also known as impact 2 that we covered early on
合作，结果证明这个 h.262 也被称为我们之前介绍过的 Impact 2
so therefore h.262 is also uh impact 2 yeah so 262 is also known as impact 2 they are the same
因此，h.262 也是呃 Impact 2 是的，所以 262 也称为 Impact 2 它们是相同的
right so it was uh because it was jointly developed by these two uh organizations okay so
是的所以是呃因为它是这两个呃组织联合开发的好吧所以
because it's covered in impact 2 already so we will not touch it here so uh the objective of
因为它已经在影响 2 中涵盖了，所以我们不会在这里触及它，所以呃目标
today's lecture is more for uh overview or quick introduction so we are not going to go into the
今天的讲座更多的是呃概述或快速介绍，所以我们不打算深入
detail in subsequent lecture we will learn more about it okay so this h.263 right is um okay
在接下来的讲座中我们将详细了解它，所以这个 h.263 权利是好的
there's actually a few different versions of it so the first version v1 is developed in 95
实际上有几个不同的版本，所以第一个版本 v1 是在 95 年开发的
okay so of course you expect the performance is better than the previous uh 261 okay so it's also
好吧，你当然期望性能比之前的呃 261 更好，好吧，所以它也是
mainly for video conferencing therefore you expect it to be fast you expect the bit rate to be low
主要用于视频会议，因此您希望它很快，您希望比特率较低
okay yeah and afterwards there's a new improvement version 2 and version 3 so for version 2 and version
好的，是的，之后有一个新的改进版本 2 和版本 3，所以对于版本 2 和版本
3 we call also called uh 263 plus and plus plus okay so these are different versions or improvement
3 我们也称之为呃 263 plus 和 plus plus 好吧，所以这些是不同的版本或改进
right okay and then afterwards things uh continue on then we move on to h.264 so h.264 again there's
好吧，然后事情继续，然后我们转向 h.264，所以 h.264 又出现了
a few common name that's being used right we can call it h.264 sometimes we also call it advanced
一些常用的名称，我们可以称之为 h.264，有时我们也称之为高级
video coding or avc okay sometimes they also call it mpeg for part 10 so all this refer to the same
视频编码或 avc 好吧，有时他们也将其称为 mpeg 第 10 部分，所以所有这些都指的是相同的
thing okay so it was standardized in 2003 right uh of course you expect since it was a later standard
事情还好，所以它是在 2003 年标准化的，呃，当然你期望的，因为它是后来的标准
right it's going to perform better than uh the previous version h.263 all right so it has a
是的，它的性能会比之前的版本 h.263 更好，所以它有一个
wide range of application like internet video computer no hd tv uh blu-ray and so on and so
应用范围广泛，例如互联网视频计算机没有高清电视呃蓝光等等
so nowadays right if you go to the internet right and if you download a video very likely the standard
所以现在如果你上网并且下载视频很可能是标准
that you are going to get is the h.264 or mp4 right if all some of you have downloaded some
如果你们所有人都下载了一些，那么您将获得的是 h.264 或 mp4
video nowadays right this is currently the most popular and dominant uh video standard at the
视频现在是正确的，这是目前最流行和占主导地位的呃视频标准
moment okay h.264 right okay and then afterwards things continue you know i mean the body continue
好吧 h.264 好吧好吧然后事情继续你知道我的意思是身体继续
to improve the standard so the next one is the h.265 all right so it's also known as a high
改进标准，所以下一个是 h.265 好吧，所以它也被称为高
evision video coding or gvc here so uh it's basic structure right in terms of the algorithm is very
evision 视频编码或 gvc 这里所以呃它的基本结构就算法而言是非常
similar to 264 okay but it has a few uh feature it can support higher resolution now 8k resolution
类似于 264 好吧，但它有一些呃功能，它可以支持更高分辨率，现在 8k 分辨率
and up to 120 frame per second right okay and also uh it's more efficient in terms of a bit
每秒高达 120 帧，好吧，而且呃，就一点而言，效率更高
rate quality trade-off right uh because typically right for a good video you want the bit rate to be
速率质量权衡是正确的，因为通常对于一个好的视频来说，您希望比特率是
low and you want the quality to be high but usually if your bit rate is low your quality
低，您希望质量高，但通常如果您的比特率低，您的质量
will not be so good and vice versa so as a whole h.265 can actually achieve this trade-off better
不会那么好，反之亦然，因此作为一个整体，h.265 实际上可以更好地实现这种权衡
than 264
超过 264
right okay so the mpeg and the h.26x series are two dominant important video compression standards
好吧，所以 mpeg 和 h.26x 系列是两个占主导地位的重要视频压缩标准
but there are also some other standards uh out there so the first one is vc1 so vc1 is uh developed
但还有一些其他标准，所以第一个标准是 vc1，所以 vc1 是开发的
by this uh society known as society of motion picture and tv television engineers right it was
这个呃协会被称为电影和电视电视工程师协会，没错，就是这样
supported by a microsoft uh window media video so these are more like no factual information
由微软呃窗口媒体视频支持，所以这些更像是没有事实信息
because if you are studying this course and people ask you know you are studying about
因为如果你正在学习这门课程并且人们问你知道你正在学习什么
video compression can you at least tell us some of the standard at least you'll be aware you know
视频压缩你能至少告诉我们一些标准吗至少你会知道你知道
these are currently some of the you know standards that's out there okay so another uh recent popular
这些是目前一些你知道的标准，好吧，所以另一个呃最近流行的标准
one is uh this vp8 so vp8 is target for a web video right the video that's embedded in the
一个是呃，这个 vp8，所以 vp8 是网络视频的目标，该视频嵌入在
internet right okay so it support this web video format and it can support up to 4k resolution
互联网没问题，所以它支持这种网络视频格式，并且最高可以支持 4k 分辨率
okay and vp9 is also developed by google right so it's an improvement to vp8 so you can see
好的，vp9 也是由 google 开发的，所以它是 vp8 的改进，所以你可以看到
its structure is actually similar to vp8 so it's an improvement but in terms of resolution now
它的结构实际上与 vp8 类似，所以它是一个改进，但在分辨率方面现在
it's better it can support up to 8k and 120 uh frame per second so yeah so these are some of the
最好它可以支持每秒 8k 和 120 uh 帧，所以是的，这些是其中的一些
popular and current major standards out there right okay so the next topic we want to very
流行的和当前的主要标准就在那里，好吧，所以下一个主题我们想要非常
quickly touch on is on the video analysis and understanding so uh early on as i mentioned for
快速触及视频分析和理解，正如我早些时候提到的
this course right there's the compression there's a video analytics and actually uh there's also
这门课程有压缩，有视频分析，实际上呃还有
going to be on the emerging direction but the part i have not finalized it so these are the a few key
将是新兴方向，但我还没有最终确定，所以这些是几个关键
expect for this particular course so under the video analysis and understanding so what we'll
期待这个特定的课程，所以根据视频分析和理解，我们会做什么
do is that we'll try to you know uh for this course these are some of the tasks we'll be studying
要做的是，我们会尽力让您知道，呃，对于本课程，这些是我们将要学习的一些任务
because even for video content and analysis now there's many many many different topics that you
因为即使对于视频内容和分析，现在也有很多很多不同的主题
can uh talk about so that's why we are going to select some no use case right on an application
呃，可以谈谈吗，这就是为什么我们要在应用程序上选择一些无用例的原因
and try to you know explain them or cover in this lecture so in this lecture some of the important
并尝试让您知道在本次讲座中解释或涵盖这些内容，因此在本次讲座中一些重要的内容
tasks that we'll cover including uh object detections and tracking okay uh post estimation for
我们将涵盖的任务包括呃物体检测和跟踪好吧呃后期估计
example how do you detect uh different poles of the human right just now you can also see from the
例如，你现在如何检测人类的不同极点，你也可以从
video that we have no for post estimation one very common things is that you can use to
我们没有用于后期评估的视频，一个非常常见的事情是您可以使用
you know study for example the ergonomics right you can use do uh jayshir recognition for example
例如，你知道研究人体工程学，你可以使用例如 jayshir 识别
recognize different hand jayshir you can use to uh once you estimate different poles on the body
一旦你估计了身体上的不同极点，你就可以识别出不同的手 jayshir
you can also use it to perform action recognition trying to find out whether they are no drinking
你还可以用它来进行动作识别，试图找出他们是否没有喝酒
water or walking or playing balls and things like that so those are the post estimation but okay we
水、散步或打球之类的事情，所以这些是事后估计，但好吧，我们
also will be covering some action recognition so you'll try to analyze different actions in
还将涵盖一些动作识别，因此您将尝试分析不同的动作
the video human actions in the video so these are some of the selected uh topics we'll cover under
视频中的人类行为，所以这些是我们将在下面讨论的一些选定的呃主题
this video analysis right okay so next i'm going to play you a few short video to explain
这个视频分析得不错，接下来我会播放一些短片来解释一下
right some of those tasks that object detection
正确处理对象检测的一些任务
yeah so next i'll try to play you a short a few short video to explain some of the
是的，接下来我会尝试播放一段简短的视频来解释一些
tasks that we have uh mentioned in case because i know that for your group your background is
我们提到的任务以防万一，因为我知道对于您的团队来说，您的背景是
very diverse you have some students which has a bit more experience in you know this AI computer
非常多样化，你有一些学生，他们在你了解这台人工智能计算机方面有更多的经验
vision but there's also a large percentage of a student who doesn't have this background so i'll
愿景，但也有很大一部分学生没有这种背景，所以我会
play you a few short video just to give you some sense about some of the tasks that we are going
给您播放一些简短的视频，让您了解我们即将完成的一些任务
to cover in the later part of lecture so that you have a certain idea so the first task that we are
在讲座的后面部分进行介绍，以便您有一定的想法，因此我们的第一个任务是
going to do is about object detection so i'll play you this video it's about two minutes plus
要做的是关于物体检测，所以我会给你播放这个视频，大约两分钟多
to explain what object detection is a pinnacle in artificial intelligence but it co-exists with us
解释什么对象检测是人工智能的顶峰但它与我们共存
in our lives hiding in plain sight we often fail to notice simple applications of object
在我们的生活中，我们经常忽视对象的简单应用
detection around us have you ever wondered how a face unlock works on your smartphone or how a
我们周围的检测您是否想知道智能手机上的面部解锁如何工作，或者如何
self-driving car operates on its own the answer is object detection so what is object detection
自动驾驶汽车自行运行答案是物体检测那么什么是物体检测
technically object detection is a technology that includes computer vision and image processing
从技术上讲，目标检测是一项包括计算机视觉和图像处理的技术
used to detect objects in images or videos sounds interesting let's break it down for you
用于检测图像或视频中的对象听起来很有趣让我们为您分解一下
using a simple example self-driving cars make use of the moving object detection technology
举一个简单的例子，自动驾驶汽车利用移动物体检测技术
where computer vision and image processing are used to determine the distance between the car
使用计算机视觉和图像处理来确定汽车之间的距离
and the moving objects to create alerts and guide the self-driving cars you must be wondering what
以及移动物体来发出警报并引导自动驾驶汽车，您一定想知道什么
is the technology behind it well artificial intelligence is the basic principle that drives
背后的技术是好人工智能是驱动的基本原理
object detection the idea is simple the data is collected through computer vision the data is then
物体检测 想法很简单 通过计算机视觉收集数据 然后将数据
fed into the model and using machine learning algorithms or deep learning algorithms inclusions
输入模型并使用机器学习算法或深度学习算法包含
are made the camera collects the image from different angles and sends it to the image
使得摄像头采集不同角度的图像并发送给图像
processing unit now based on how the model was trained and what the training data was the results
处理单元现在基于模型的训练方式以及训练数据的结果
are laid out to the system in the form of alerts or instructions like how far the object is if the
以警报或指令的形式向系统展示，例如如果物体
object is moving or if the object has stopped object detection has also been paving a glorious
物体正在移动或者物体已经停止，物体检测也已经铺平了辉煌
path for the surveillance industry traffic tracking systems activity recognition even sentiment
监控行业交通跟踪系统活动识别甚至情绪的路径
analysis through object detection are all possible now surveillance has picked up a lot of pace with
现在，通过对象检测进行分析都是可能的，监视已经加快了步伐
object detection with increasing efficiency in object detection technology it is evident that
目标检测随着目标检测技术效率的不断提高，很明显
artificial intelligence is on the rise and it will eventually create a lot of job opportunities
人工智能正在兴起，最终将创造大量就业机会
in the coming years as well at eureka's postgraduate program in ai ml in collaboration
未来几年，以及尤里卡人工智能机器学习研究生项目的合作
with nid varangal will help you in mastering such advanced ai concepts with the help of experience
nid varangal 将帮助您借助经验掌握此类先进的人工智能概念
okay so therefore you can see from this video the objective of object detection is to try to
好的，因此您可以从这段视频中看到，对象检测的目标是尝试
detect different instances of objects in the scene so there's actually object detection even though
检测场景中对象的不同实例，因此实际上存在对象检测，即使
it's a more fundamental task but it actually also have various challenges for example you need to
这是一项更基本的任务，但实际上也面临着各种挑战，例如您需要
be able to handle different imaging condition yeah different viewpoint now the size whether it's big
能够处理不同的成像条件是的，不同的视角，现在的尺寸是否大
object or small object sometimes different lighting condition for example currently i have one
物体或小物体有时会有不同的照明条件，例如目前我有一个
particular project with a company so for this particular project we are trying to put some
与一家公司合作的特定项目，因此对于这个特定项目，我们正在尝试投入一些
camera in the car cabin and try to you know analyze the you know the actions and the behaviors of the
在车舱内安装摄像头并尝试分析您知道的动作和行为
drivers as well as the passengers as well as detect different objects in the car so this could be used
驾驶员和乘客以及检测车内的不同物体，因此可以使用
for example in application for example the one that we mentioned in wuhan the
例如在应用中，例如我们在武汉提到的那个
low ball quite power right so if you go into the car you know if you try to scratch their car they
低球相当有力，所以如果你走进车里，你就知道如果你试图刮伤他们的车，他们
will see that you're doing something that you're not supposed to be or you live behind something
会发现你正在做一些你不应该做的事情或者你生活在某些事情背后
they will actually alert you so yeah for example in car environment one of the challenge that you
他们实际上会提醒您，是的，例如在汽车环境中，这是您面临的挑战之一
have is the lighting condition yeah sometimes no it can be a bit too dark in the car environment
有的是照明条件 是的，有时没有，车内环境可能有点太暗
so therefore you need to investigate different issues like using different
因此，您需要调查不同的问题，例如使用不同的
sensing modality for example just now the camera that we talked about using the rgb camera as well
传感方式 例如刚才我们谈到的使用 RGB 相机的相机
as the no infrared okay near infrared capture this information and then try to fuse them
因为没有红外线可以，近红外线捕获此信息，然后尝试融合它们
to help you to perform object detection as well as action recognition so therefore
帮助您执行物体检测和动作识别，因此
there are actually still quite a lot of uh no challenges in problems such as object detection
实际上在物体检测等问题上还有很多呃没有挑战
okay so the next uh video that we are going to show is the object tracking so what's the meaning
好的，我们要展示的下一个视频是对象跟踪，这是什么意思
of object tracking so we can yeah pretty much as the name suggests is that once you detect the object
物体跟踪，所以我们可以是的，顾名思义，一旦您检测到物体
you want to track the movement of the object okay you want to track the movement so there's many
你想跟踪物体的运动 好吧，你想跟踪运动，所以有很多
uh cases why you may want to do that for example for separate security application and so on yeah
呃，为什么你可能想要这样做，例如对于单独的安全应用程序等等是的
yeah so let me just play you this short video on object tracking
是的，让我给你播放一段关于对象跟踪的短视频
so
所以
okay yeah so for example now you can see from the video quite clearly what's the objective of the
好的，是的，例如，现在您可以从视频中清楚地看到其目标是什么
object tracking is that you want to track the movement of the person so what are some common
对象跟踪是你想要跟踪人的运动那么有哪些常见的
challenges in this object tracking one common one is the occlusion if you're for example the
此对象跟踪中的挑战之一常见的挑战是遮挡，例如，如果您是
person you are trying to track they go you know behind a particular structure okay say this
你试图追踪的人 他们是你认识的某个特定结构背后的人 好吧，这么说
building so part of my body now is obscured so when i move out and reappear can you still track
建筑物现在我身体的一部分被遮挡了所以当我搬出去并重新出现时你还能追踪吗
that it's the same person so these are some challenge other things include for example if
这是同一个人，所以这些是一些挑战，其他事情包括，例如，如果
you're a two person you know walking in opposite direction right and afterwards say suppose they
你们认识两个人，朝相反的方向走，然后说假设他们
cross over would you somehow switch the id the track number you would think that is now different
交叉你会以某种方式改变你认为现在不同的轨道编号吗
person or if these two person they meet here and afterwards they move separate in a separate way
一个人，或者如果这两个人在这里相遇，然后他们以不同的方式分开
if you just follow the trajectory path you will thought that you know this person is becoming here
如果你只是沿着轨迹路径走，你会认为你知道这个人正在成为这里
and this person is becoming here but actually sometimes they could just meet and then they're
这个人正在成为这里，但实际上有时他们可以见面，然后他们就
separate so therefore id switch the switch of different id is also a challenge in this object
分开所以id切换不同id的切换也是这个对象的一个​​挑战
tracking right so let's continue to look at some of the other right okay so this video shows you
跟踪正确的所以让我们继续看看其他一些正确的好吧所以这个视频向您展示
post estimation so post estimation pretty much means that you want to estimate the key point
事后估计所以事后估计几乎意味着你想要估计关键点
or the key important joint of the body so it can be a full body post estimation or it can be for
或身体的关键重要关节，因此它可以是全身后估计，也可以是
example your facial post estimation some of the key point on your face or some of the key point on
例如，你的脸部位置估计你脸上的一些关键点或身上的一些关键点
your head so these are some a few different possible variations of the post estimation
你的头脑所以这些是事后估计的一些不同的可能变化
so let me just play for you this short video
那么让我为你播放这个短片
so
所以
you can see it's trying to estimate all the important key points right
你可以看到它试图正确估计所有重要的关键点
so once you estimate this important key point you can use to analyze the actions of the
因此，一旦您估计了这个重要的关键点，您就可以用来分析
you know the person actually in gyms is a very natural no use case of post estimation
你知道，实际上在健身房里的人是一个非常自然的事后估计的用例
I used to have one research staff right he he used to work in a project in uh Korea yeah and
我曾经有一名研究人员，他曾经在韩国的一个项目中工作，是的，
they're actually doing exactly this which is using the post estimation to analyze the movement of the
他们实际上正在做这件事，即使用后估计来分析物体的运动
of the person who do the workout in a gym yeah
在健身房锻炼的人是的
so
所以
they should bring a mattress then he can fold up a bit faster
他们应该带一个床垫，这样他就可以折叠得更快一点
oh
哦
yeah so in the past I still remember there was a project which is they're using a post estimation
是的，所以在过去，我仍然记得有一个项目，他们正在使用事后估算
to do the uh Parkinson disease progression you know what's a Parkinson disease right
要了解帕金森病的进展情况，您知道什么是帕金森病吗？
no Parkinson disease is characterized by no uh we start when you walk especially for old older
没有帕金森病的特点是没有呃我们从你走路的时候开始特别是对于老年人
person when you walk actually your swing of the hand is asymmetric one hand swing normally the
当你走路的时候，你的手的摆动是不对称的，通常一只手摆动
other hand doesn't swing a lot actually I also notice sometimes when I walk that's how I walk
另一只手实际上摆动幅度不大，有时我走路时也注意到这就是我走路的方式
so actually it can be used to analyze for example whether your Parkinson disease has deteriorated
所以实际上它可以用来分析你的帕金森病是否恶化
over time okay so the next one is actually on uh action recognition so action recognition for
随着时间的推移，好的，所以下一个实际上是呃动作识别，所以动作识别
this video is mainly focusing on sports video but it can be a lot more for example in the context of
该视频主要关注体育视频，但也可以有更多内容，例如在
a factory uh kind of assembly task you can analyze whether this particular worker is performing what
工厂呃一种装配任务，你可以分析这个特定的工人是否正在执行什么
task whether it's tightening tightening a nuts no applying some screw and so on so currently we are
任务是否是拧紧螺母，是否使用螺钉等等，所以目前我们正在
also uh no discussing with a uh a company right to know uh try to perform this action recognition
也呃不与呃公司讨论有权知道呃尝试执行此行动认可
for worker who is trying to perform some assembly tasks yeah so uh but for this video is for a sports video
对于试图执行一些组装任务的工人来说是的，但是这个视频是体育视频
right so there are different action whether it's like you know dribbling the balls
是的，所以无论是像你知道的运球一样，都有不同的动作
no whether it's like no trying to block no and and so on so there's a different actions
否 是否类似于“否”试图阻止“否”等等，因此有不同的操作
for this particular sports video okay but in general case of course it can be a lot broader
对于这个特定的体育视频，好的，但在一般情况下，当然它可以更广泛
okay like the one that I mentioned trying to analyze different actions in assembly tasks
好的，就像我提到的尝试分析装配任务中的不同操作一样
or in a more generous setting to try out find out whether you are drinking water you're walking
或者在更慷慨的环境中尝试看看您是否在步行时喝水
no or you are smoking and so on
不，或者你正在吸烟等等
okay so the next uh video this one is called egocentric human object interactions so egocentric
好吧，下一个呃视频这个叫做以自我为中心的人类对象交互所以以自我为中心
means that is no the viewpoint is like the human viewpoint the first person perspective viewpoint
意思是没有像人类的观点一样的观点第一人称视角观点
and human object interaction as the name suggests the interaction between human and objects so in
人与物交互，顾名思义就是人与物体之间的交互，所以在
many of the tasks are when the worker is trying to learn something at the form certain tasks
许多任务是当工人试图从某些任务中学习一些东西时
you know we need to understand what the worker is doing right how does it manipulate the objects
你知道我们需要了解工人正在做什么，它是如何操纵对象的
and so on so this is also one topic which is known as an egocentric human object interaction
等等，这也是一个被称为以自我为中心的人机交互的主题
okay
好的
it's from interactions between hands with objects
它来自于手与物体之间的相互作用
audio can be a prime discriminator for actions such as washing or frying
音频可以成为洗涤或煎炸等动作的主要鉴别因素
it can also differentiate between objects within actions such as
它还可以区分动作中的对象，例如
putting a plate versus putting a bag
放盘子与放袋子
okay audio captures sounds of actions out of the camera's field of view such as eating
好的音频可以捕获相机视野之外的动作声音，例如吃饭的声音
but can also capture irrelevant background music
但也可以捕捉不相关的背景音乐
we propose mid-level fusion of three modalities rgb flow and audio for audio we extract the raw
我们建议对三种模式 RGB 流和音频进行中级融合，我们提取原始音频
waveform from the sound stream of the video which we transform into a spectrogram
我们将视频声音流中的波形转换为频谱图
convolutional features are pooled and mid-level fusion is learned through feature concatenation
卷积特征被池化，并通过特征串联学习中层融合
we learn the action as multitask verb and noun classifiers importantly we train using
我们将动作学习为多任务动词和名词分类器，重要的是我们使用
asynchronous fusion we fuse modalities with a range of temporal offsets within a temporal
异步融合我们将模态与时间范围内的一系列时间偏移融合在一起
binding window evidence in neuroscience points to the presence of such temporal
神经科学中的结合窗口证据表明这种时间的存在
binding windows across sensory input in humans within each binding window modality samples are
每个结合窗口模态样本内跨人类感觉输入的结合窗口是
randomly selected tbw's are sparsely sampled within the action and could be overlapping
随机选择的 tbw 在动作中稀疏采样并且可能重叠
predictions are temporally aggregated by averaging to obtain video level multimodal predictions
通过平均来临时聚合预测以获得视频级多模态预测
importantly we first bind and fuse modalities within windows before temporal aggregation of
重要的是，我们首先在窗口内绑定和融合模态，然后再进行时间聚合
different windows tbn is trained end to end where all modalities are trained simultaneously
不同的窗口 tbn 进行端到端训练，所有模式同时训练
and the weights are shared over time we next present qualitative results of tbn on the epic
并且权重随着时间的推移而共享，接下来我们将展示 tbn 在史诗中的定性结果
kitchens data set
厨房数据集
so
所以
okay yeah so this is one of the earlier works that was done to perform human object interaction
好的，是的，这是为执行人类对象交互而完成的早期作品之一
actually this human object interaction is very difficult to do it's still very challenging
实际上这种人机交互很难做到，仍然很有挑战性
because there's a lot of challenges for example you need to perform action detection or temporal
因为存在很多挑战，例如您需要执行动作检测或时间
video segmentation right from what you see that actually no a lot of the earlier for example action
从您所看到的来看，视频分割实际上没有很多早期的示例动作
recognitions are usually the video we chop it into small segments okay and then for each of the video
识别通常是我们将视频切成小段，然后针对每个视频
segment we try to you know classify what kind of action it is but for a continuous video like this
我们试图让您知道这是什么类型的动作，但是对于像这样的连续视频
given a particular video you need to divide into different segments so that different
给定一个特定的视频，您需要分成不同的片段，以便不同的片段
segments actually correspond to different action so that particular task is known as a temporal
片段实际上对应于不同的动作，因此特定的任务被称为时间
video segmentation so that one even to do that to nicely cut it into different video segment
视频分割，这样就可以将其很好地切割成不同的视频片段
in itself is already a challenge and also from just now you can see the video when the person
本身就已经是一个挑战，而且从刚才开始，你可以看到视频中的人
is doing some tasks there's lots of noise sometimes he will just move around and then go and do
正在做一些任务，有很多噪音，有时他会四处走动，然后就去做
something else and we come back so how do we recognize those actions are not of interest to
别的事情，我们回来了，那么我们如何认识到这些行为是不感兴趣的
us and they are noise yeah so there's also for example when you're dealing with this object in
我们和他们都是噪音，是的，所以还有例如当你在处理这个对象时
real life there's lots of background clutters and you know different objects that is not interested
现实生活中有很多杂乱的背景，并且你知道不同的不感兴趣的对象
that you are not interested in so it's in short this is still a very difficult and challenging problem
你不感兴趣所以总之这仍然是一个非常困难和具有挑战性的问题
okay so next I'll just very briefly talk about some of the emerging topics right so in
好的，接下来我将非常简短地讨论一些新兴主题，所以在
recent years of course generative AI is becoming very you know important so I think many of you
当然，近年来，生成式人工智能变得非常重要，所以我想你们中的许多人
probably have seen like chat gbt whereas you can generate the new content it can become a chat box
可能见过像聊天 GBT 这样的东西，你可以生成新的内容，它可以成为一个聊天框
it can become an assistant you can interact with them in a very natural way other things like
它可以成为一个助手，您可以以非常自然的方式与他们互动，例如
them in a very natural way other things like you know for example image generation so how many of
它们以一种非常自然的方式，像你知道的其他事情，例如图像生成，那么有多少
you have used some image generation tools like you know mid-journey or stable diffusion
您使用过一些图像生成工具，例如您所知道的中途或稳定扩散
yeah I can see a few person raising their hand so you can see no reason in recent year right if
是的，我可以看到有几个人举手，所以你看不出近年来有什么原因，如果
you want to generate text generate image this is actually a very hot topic in uh in recent year
你想要生成文本生成图像这实际上是呃近年来非常热门的话题
because in the past in the past for AI it tends to be discriminative right in other words for
因为过去对于人工智能来说它往往是歧视性的，换句话说对于
example in the past AI tends to try to classify an image or video into this category or that
过去的例子人工智能倾向于尝试将图像或视频分类为这个类别或那个类别
category so they cannot generate new content but in recent year right no uh this in I think year
类别，因此他们无法生成新内容，但近年来，不，呃，我认为这一年
2018 forwards this generative AI is becoming very important because it can generate new content
2018年，这种生成式人工智能变得非常重要，因为它可以生成新内容
so generative AI is a class of model that can generate new content such as a text image audio
所以生成式人工智能是一类可以生成新内容（例如文本图像音频）的模型
okay and so on so if you are referring to for example text generation one very popular model is
好的等等，如果您指的是文本生成，一个非常流行的模型是
the gbt generative pre-trained transformer okay so for this course we will also touch on this a
GBT 生成式预训练变压器 好的，所以在本课程中我们还将涉及这一点
little bit later okay and then for image generation uh no a well-known technique is a stable diffusion
稍后，好吧，然后进行图像生成，嗯，不，众所周知的技术是稳定扩散
okay so it support various types of application like chat box you ask question they will answer
好的，它支持各种类型的应用程序，例如聊天框，您提出问题他们会回答
you okay content uh generation for example you can use the transformer to ask them to write a novel
你可以内容呃一代例如你可以使用变压器要求他们写一本小说
write a story okay and virtual assistant for those of you who have watched uh this interaction the
写一个故事好吧，为那些看过这个互动的人提供虚拟助手
recent uh chat gb this gbt 4o you will know that no you can actually interact with them in a very
最近呃聊天 gb 这个 gbt 4o 你会知道，不，你实际上可以以非常好的方式与他们互动
natural way right so another kind of a very important emerging direction in recent year
自然的方式是正确的，所以近年来另一种非常重要的新兴方向
is the idea of this foundation model so what's the foundation model so foundation model is a
是这个基础模型的想法 那么什么是基础模型 所以基础模型是
class of model that are trained on large scale broad data that can be adapted or fine-tuned to
在大规模广泛数据上进行训练的模型类别，可以调整或微调
wide range of downstream tasks or application so in a more traditional way you know in the past
广泛的下游任务或应用程序，因此以您过去知道的更传统的方式
when people want to say suppose they want to solve a particular problem what they need to do
当人们想说假设他们想解决某个特定问题时他们需要做什么
for example if you want to recognize different plants in singapore right so suppose if you join
例如，如果您想识别新加坡的不同植物，那么假设您加入
a company and the company asks you to develop a mobile app that can recognize different plants
一家公司和公司要求你开发一个可以识别不同植物的移动应用程序
in singapore what do you have to do so if you think about it so what it means likely is that
在新加坡你必须做什么如果你想一想那么这可能意味着
you have to go and collect some you know images your plant images in singapore and then you have
你必须去收集一些你知道的图像，你在新加坡的植物图像，然后你就有了
to employ an expert to tell you what this different you know categories of plants it is and afterwards
聘请专家告诉您您所知道的植物类别是什么，然后
you need to spend lots of money to do that collection annotation and afterwards you need
你需要花很多钱来做这个集合注释，然后你需要
to train this model from the scratch to develop your uh plan recognition or classification algorithm
从头开始训练该模型以开发您的呃计划识别或分类算法
so that's in the past that means for each problems that you have you need to collect the data set
所以这已经过去了，这意味着对于您遇到的每个问题，您都需要收集数据集
you need to train a AI model and then afterwards then you can deploy it so different use case you
你需要训练一个人工智能模型，然后你可以部署它，这样你就可以在不同的用例中
need to collect different data set and you need to train a new model so this of course you can see
需要收集不同的数据集，并且需要训练一个新模型，因此您当然可以看到
it's very expensive because data collection you know is very expensive and annotation is very
它非常昂贵，因为您知道数据收集非常昂贵并且注释非常昂贵
expensive so this foundation model is basically based on this idea is that you're going to train
昂贵，所以这个基础模型基本上基于这个想法，就是你要训练
on a very large scale data so this large scale data can be billions of images right it's broad
在非常大规模的数据上，所以这种大规模数据可以是数十亿张图像，它很广泛
data that means you try to train over a wide range of different types of data okay and afterwards
数据意味着您尝试训练各种不同类型的数据，然后就可以了
once you have fully trained it you can then use it to adapt or do it some fine tuning so that you can
一旦你完全训练了它，你就可以用它来适应或做一些微调，这样你就可以
then use it to deploy for your specific application yeah so that's the high level idea so you can see
然后用它来部署您的特定应用程序是的，这是高级想法，您可以看到
this is the high level idea you have lots of data right it's a large scale broad data you use it to
这是一个高层次的想法，你拥有大量数据，这是你用它来处理的大规模广泛数据
train a very big foundation model so this foundation model is very big you have seen many different
训练一个非常大的基础模型所以这个基础模型非常大你已经看到了很多不同的
things already so afterwards once you have this foundation model depending on what is your
一旦你有了这个基础模型，事情就已经如此，这取决于你的
downstream application you can then use it to do some adaptation or simple fine tuning right
然后，您可以使用下游应用程序进行一些调整或简单的微调
so that you can then use it to address some specific problem so therefore this foundation
这样你就可以用它来解决一些特定的问题，因此这个基础
model in recent years is actually past one or two years is becoming very important okay and many
近年来的模型实际上过去一两年变得非常重要，好吧，很多
people are trying to spend time to develop this different way for example to adapt your big
人们试图花时间来开发这种不同的方式，例如适应你的大
foundation model so some examples of foundation models are large language model for example gpt
基础模型，因此基础模型的一些示例是大型语言模型，例如 gpt
that we have seen and vision language model model that combine the vision and the language
我们看到的视觉语言模型是视觉和语言相结合的模型
so a very well known example is the clip model
所以一个非常著名的例子是剪辑模型
okay so next we have a short video actually the video is long but i'm not going to play the
好的，接下来我们有一个短视频，实际上视频很长，但我不会播放
whole video i just play a short segment right just to give you a feel know how is the current
整个视频我只播放一小段，只是为了让大家感受一下当前情况如何
train right as well as some background in generative ai and foundation model so let me just play this
正确训练以及生成人工智能和基础模型的一些背景，所以让我玩这个
particular video for you
为您准备的特别视频
ever since computers were invented they've really just been glorified calculators machines that
自从计算机被发明以来，它们实际上只是被美化的计算器机器
execute the exact instructions given to them by the programmers but something incredible is
执行程序员给他们的确切指令，但令人难以置信的是
happening now computers have started gaining the ability to learn and think and communicate
现在发生的事情计算机已经开始获得学习、思考和交流的能力
just like we do they can do creative intellectual work that previously only humans could do we call
就像我们一样，他们可以做以前只有人类才能做的创造性智力工作，我们称之为
this technology generative ai and you may have encountered it already through products like chat
这项技术是生成式人工智能，您可能已经通过聊天等产品遇到过它
gpt basically intelligence is now available as a service kind of like a giant
gpt 基本上智能现在可以作为一种服务使用，就像一个巨人一样
sky that anyone can talk to it's not perfect but it is surprisingly capable and it is improving
任何人都可以与之交谈的天空它并不完美，但它的能力令人惊讶，并且正在不断改进
at an exponential rate this is a big deal it's going to affect just about every person and company
以指数级的速度，这是一件大事，它将影响到几乎每个人和公司
on the planet positively or negatively this video is here to help you understand what generative ai
这个视频的目的是帮助您了解生成式人工智能对地球的积极或消极影响
is all about in practical terms beyond the hype the better you understand this technology as a
从实际角度来看，这一切都超出了炒作，您对这项技术的了解越深入
person team or company the better equipped you will be to survive and thrive in the age of ai
个人、团队或公司越有能力在人工智能时代生存和发展
so here's the silly but useful mental model for this you have einstein in your basement in
所以这是一个愚蠢但有用的心理模型，你的地下室里有爱因斯坦
fact everyone does and by einstein i really mean the combination of every smart person who ever
事实上每个人都这样做，爱因斯坦的意思是每个聪明人的结合
lived you can talk to einstein whenever you want he has instant access to the sum of all human
只要你愿意，你就可以随时与爱因斯坦交谈，他可以立即获得全人类的总和
knowledge and will answer anything you want within seconds never running out of patience he can also
知识，并会在几秒钟内回答你想要的任何问题，永远不会失去耐心，他也可以
take on any role you want a comedian poet doctor coach and will be an expert within that field
扮演任何你想要的角色喜剧演员诗人医生教练并将成为该领域的专家
he has some human-like limitations though he can make mistakes he can jump to conclusions he can
他有一些像人类一样的局限性，尽管他会犯错误，但他可以仓促下结论
misunderstand you but the biggest limitation is actually your imagination and your ability to
误解你，但最大的限制其实是你的想象力和你的能力
communicate effectively with him this skill is known as prompt engineering and in the age of ai
与他进行有效的沟通，这项技能被称为快速工程，在人工智能时代
this is as essential as reading and writing most people vastly underestimate what this einstein
这与阅读和写作一样重要，大多数人都大大低估了爱因斯坦的能力
in your basement can do it's like going to the real einstein and asking him to proofread a high
在你的地下室可以做到这就像去真正的爱因斯坦并请他校对一个高
school report or hiring a world-class five-star chef and having him chop onions the more you
学校报告或聘请世界一流的五星级厨师并让他切洋葱越多
interact with einstein the more you will discover surprising and powerful ways for him to help you
与爱因斯坦互动越多，你就会发现他以令人惊讶和强大的方式来帮助你
or your company okay enough fluffy metaphors let's clarify some terms ai as you probably know stands
或者你的公司好吧，足够蓬松的隐喻让我们澄清一些你可能知道的术语人工智能
for artificial intelligence ai is not new feels like machine learning and computer vision have
对于人工智能来说，人工智能并不新鲜，就像机器学习和计算机视觉一样
been around for decades whenever you see a youtube recommendation or a web search result or whenever
几十年来，每当您看到 YouTube 推荐或网络搜索结果或每当
you get a credit card transaction approved that's traditional ai in action generative ai is ai that
你得到了一笔信用卡交易的批准，这是传统的人工智能在行动，生成式人工智能是人工智能
generates new original content rather than just finding or classifying existing content that's the
生成新的原始内容，而不仅仅是查找或分类现有内容
g and gpt for example large language models or lms are a type of generative ai that can communicate
g 和 gpt 例如大型语言模型或 lms 是一种可以交流的生成人工智能
using normal human language chat gpt is a product by the company open ai it started as an lm
使用正常的人类语言聊天 gpt 是 open ai 公司的产品，它最初是作为 lm 开始的
essentially an advanced chat bot using a new architecture called the transformer architecture
本质上是一个高级聊天机器人，使用称为变压器架构的新架构
which by the way is the t and gpt it is so fluent at human language that anyone can use it you don't
顺便说一句，这是 t 和 gpt，它对人类语言非常流利，任何人都可以使用它，而你却不会
need to be an ai expert or programmer and that's kind of what triggered the whole revolution
需要成为人工智能专家或程序员，这就是引发整个革命的原因
so how does it actually work well a large language model is an artificial neural network basically a
那么它实际上是如何运作良好的一个大型语言模型是一个人工神经网络，基本上是一个
bunch of numbers or parameters connected to each other similar to how our brain is a bunch of
一堆相互连接的数字或参数，类似于我们的大脑是一堆
neurons or brain cells connected to each other neural networks only deal with numbers you send
相互连接的神经元或脑细胞神经网络仅处理您发送的数字
in numbers and depending on how the parameters are set all the numbers come out but any kind of
在数字中，根据参数的设置方式，所有数字都会出来，但任何类型的
content such as text or images can be represented as numbers so let's say i write dogs are when i
文本或图像等内容可以表示为数字，所以假设我写狗是当我
send that to a large language model that gets converted to numbers processed by the neural
将其发送到大型语言模型，该模型将转换为由神经网络处理的数字
network and then the resulting numbers are converted back into text in this case the word
网络，然后将结果数字转换回文本，在本例中为单词
animals dogs are animals so yeah this is basically a guess the next word machine the interesting part
动物 狗是动物所以是的这基本上是一个猜测下一个单词机器有趣的部分
is if we take that output and combine it with input and send it through the model again then
就是如果我们获取该输出并将其与输入组合并再次通过模型发送它
it will continue adding new words that's what's going on behind the scenes when you type something
它会继续添加新单词，这就是您输入内容时幕后发生的事情
in chat gpt in this case for example it generated a whole story and i can continue this indefinitely
例如，在聊天 gpt 中，它生成了一个完整的故事，我可以无限期地继续这个故事
by adding more prompts a large language model may have billions or even trillions of parameters
通过添加更多提示，大型语言模型可能拥有数十亿甚至数万亿个参数
that's why they're called large so how are all these numbers set well not through manual
这就是为什么它们被称为大的原因，那么所有这些数字如何不通过手动设置好
programming that would be impossible but through training just like babies learning to speak a
编程是不可能的，但通过训练就像婴儿学习说话一样
baby isn't told how to speak she doesn't get an instruction manual instead she listens to people
婴儿没有被告知如何说话，她没有得到指导手册，而是听别人说话
speaking around her and when she's heard enough she starts seeing the pattern she speaks a few
在她周围说话，当她听得足够多时，她开始看到她说的模式
words at first to the delight of her parents and then later on full sentences similarly during a
一开始是让她父母高兴的话语，后来是类似的完整句子。
training period the language model is fed a mind-boggling amount of text to learn from mostly
训练期间，语言模型被输入大量令人难以置信的文本来学习
from internet sources it then plays guess the next word with all of this over and over again
从互联网来源，然后它会一遍又一遍地猜测下一个单词
and the parameters are automatically tweaked until it starts getting really good at predicting the
并且参数会自动调整，直到它开始真正擅长预测
next word this is called backpropagation which is a fancy term for oh i guessed wrong i better change
下一个词这称为反向传播，这是一个奇特的术语，“哦，我猜错了，我最好改变一下”
something however to become truly useful a model also needs to undergo human training this is called
然而，要变得真正有用​​，模型还需要接受人类训练，这称为
reinforcement learning with human feedback and it involves thousands of hours of humans painstakingly
具有人类反馈的强化学习，需要人类花费数千小时的艰苦努力
testing and evaluating output from the model and giving feedback kind of like training a dog with
测试和评估模型的输出并提供反馈，就像训练狗一样
a clicker to reinforce good behavior that's why a model like gpt won't tell you how to rob a bank
一个强化良好行为的答题器，这就是为什么像 gpt 这样的模型不会告诉你如何抢劫银行
it knows very well how to rob a bank but through human training it has learned that it shouldn't
它非常清楚如何抢劫银行，但通过人类训练，它知道它不应该
help people commit crimes when training is done the model is mostly frozen other than some fine
训练完成后帮助人们犯罪，除了一些罚款外，模型大部分都被冻结
tuning that can happen later that's what the p stands for in gpt pre-trained although in the
稍后可能会进行的调整，这就是 gpt 预训练中的 p 代表的意思，尽管在
future we will probably have models that can learn continuously rather than just during training and
未来我们可能会拥有能够持续学习的模型，而不仅仅是在训练期间和
fine tuning now although chat gpt kind of got the ball rolling gpt isn't the only model out there
现在正在微调，尽管聊天 gpt 有点让球滚动 gpt 不是唯一的模型
in fact new models are sprouting like mushrooms they vary a lot in terms of speed capability and
事实上，新型号如雨后春笋般涌现，它们在速度能力和性能方面差异很大。
cost some can be downloaded and run locally others are only online some are free or open source
有些可以下载并在本地运行，有些只能在线使用，有些是免费或开源的
others are commercial products some are super easy to use while others require complicated
有些是商业产品，有些非常易于使用，而另一些则需要复杂的
technical setup some are specialized for certain use cases others are more general and can be used
技术设置有些专门用于某些用例，其他则更通用并且可以使用
for almost anything and some are baked into products in the form of co-pilots or chat windows
几乎适用于任何事物，有些以副驾驶或聊天窗口的形式融入到产品中
it's it's the wild west just keep in mind that you generally get what you pay for so with a free
这是狂野的西部，请记住，你通常会得到你付出的代价，所以免费
model you may just be getting a smart high school student in your basement rather than einstein
模型你可能只是在你的地下室里找到一个聪明的高中生而不是爱因斯坦
the difference between for example gpt 3.5 and gpt 4 is massive note that there are different
例如，gpt 3.5 和 gpt 4 之间的差异是巨大的，请注意，有不同的
types of generative ai models that generate different types of content text-to-text models
生成不同类型内容的文本到文本模型的生成人工智能模型的类型
like gpt4 take text as input and generate text as output the text can be natural language but it can
像 gpt4 一样，将文本作为输入并生成文本作为输出，文本可以是自然语言，但也可以
also be structured information like code and json or html i use this a lot myself to generate
也可以是结构化信息，例如代码和 json 或 html 我自己经常使用它来生成
code when programming it saves an incredible amount of time and
编程时编写代码可以节省大量时间
yeah so yeah i guess i'll probably stop here because i can see some students starting to
是的，所以是的，我想我可能会停在这里，因为我可以看到一些学生开始
prepare to leave right okay so anyway it's quite an interesting video right you can actually go
准备离开吧好吧，无论如何，这是一个非常有趣的视频，你实际上可以走了
and i provide the link you have go and i've looked uh just give me a few more seconds i'm
我提供了你已经去的链接，我已经看过了，呃，再给我几秒钟，我
trying to finish this okay so in this lecture we cover the following topic okay see you
试图完成这个，好吧，所以在本次讲座中，我们将讨论以下主题，好的，再见
next week
下周
you
你